Did you see that transition just now?
Did you see the weight slid over?
That was nice.
That's right.
Guys, it's time for Isaac.
I've got carrots, coffee, and water.
Cheers.
And a minus 14 streak.
It's not looking good!
Oh man, we gotta fix that immediately.
We gotta do an Azazel warmup.
We gotta get a quick Azazel win in there.
Azazel warmup.
I gotta break that streak.
I can't look at that minus 14 anymore.
It's too much.
Wait, we're cursed already.
Oh, that's not a good start, but it doesn't matter.
As Azazel, you can only win.
I really shouldn't say this, because any time I don't win, I'm gonna look like a dumbass now.
So, I really should be saying, I'm probably gonna lose.
You know, it's gonna be unlucky items.
I'm not gonna find anything else.
Oh, wait a minute.
That's the library right there.
Nice.
We gotta find a key.
Evil.
Nice.
Kingdom keys.
Got one there.
I think I will use it on the library.
Also, you wanna see something cool?
I made notes.
There they are.
These are the notes I have right now.
Step my foot, I can't stop.
I went back in the VOD and noted down everything that happened with the stepity stepity step.
So yeah, there it is.
You like that?
I like it.
We're gonna be filling that out today.
Anarchist cookbook.
Randomly placed troll bombs.
That sounds horrible.
Jumps in the direction he's currently moving.
See, why do I always get stuff like this on Azazel?
How about I get stuff like this on characters where I can't fly?
You know?
Like, what the hell, man?
I guess I'm taking this.
Actually, I should be taking both.
Because then I have... Hold on.
Whoops.
I misclicked.
That was not my intention.
I didn't even realize I had the fool on me.
Anyway, what I was trying to say is, I really should be taking both because then I have two out of three on bookworm, right?
So if I get another book, I'm gonna be a bookworm.
I don't think I've ever had that, but you know.
So jump is not gonna be useful, but what I have now could become useful if I need to destroy things with bombs, right?
That one we're gonna save.
Oh god.
Wait, what happened?
Oh, even fire.
I see.
Nice.
That was a good room.
Guys, I am feeling frickin' spectacular today.
It's hard to explain, but I'm just... I have that feeling, you know?
That everything is gonna be alright.
And you know what?
That's gonna apply to you as well.
It's gonna rub off on you.
You will also be alright.
Everything's gonna be alright.
Get him out of the equation.
There we go.
Wonderful.
Now, the boss is inviting us for a dance.
I say no to that, because I can't dance.
That's not true.
I can do a little bit of dancing.
Yo, okay.
The drive-by is the way to deal with these people.
Yeah, the more I move against flies, the better.
And look at this over here.
We got a tinted rock.
But no bombs, exactly.
What would we do with bombs?
I gotta be precise, though.
Ah, shit.
So I guess you wanna use it in the corner?
You don't wanna bomb, because then they appear on the other side?
I think that's how that works.
They definitely never appear next to me, so this is what I will do from now on.
Spawning flies, not on my watch.
Oh, we got item.
Is that... Wait, what is that?
Haven't I had that before?
Parasitoid?
It's a spider baby.
Chance to fire exact tears that spawn one blue spider or fly upon striking an enemy.
Exact tears also slow enemies struck and spawn a small pool of slowing creep-on impact.
Increases with luck.
Okay.
So when I shoot, right?
Small chance to spawn it when I shoot?
Maybe it's useless on me, because I have the laser.
Or maybe it's only on impact.
Let me see again.
Chance to fire exact... Yeah, we don't use tears, so it's useless for me.
I could go in there, but since I accidentally used my full, I shouldn't go in there.
Damn.
That's too bad.
I need to go and try and get a bomb here.
Whoa!
Right, infested.
Aw, come on.
Nah!
Oh, wait, I haven't been here.
Yeah, bro!
Okay, we can use that to go into the other room.
Curse room.
Oh, yeah.
Thank you, flies.
Don't... Oh, it's kind of a waste, actually.
Man, no bombs, huh?
Not even enough with my book here.
Okay, so I think we've cleared everything.
So here's the plan.
I'm gonna walk in here.
Oh, bomb!
We got a bomb!
Weaker effect of a random rune.
I'm not sure what runes are, actually.
Random rune.
I'm gonna try it for science.
Rune shard.
I see.
That's gonna lead to the next level, so I'm not gonna do it.
We're gonna teleport to the boss room.
We're gonna kill the boss, and we're gonna go back out.
And we're gonna use the bomb to destroy the rock.
That's the plan.
Wait, why is that so slow?
Oh, was that my little spider thingy?
I think it was.
Okay.
Smooth as hell.
Moms heals, more range.
That's good for me.
Minor contact damage to enemies.
I'm sorry if you can hear the washing machine in the back.
It's going crazy right now.
It's in that last stage where it just has, like, 5,870 RPMs.
You know?
It's a lot.
I could also open one of these.
You know what, why not?
Oh, totally worth it.
Oh, my god.
We even got a bomb out of it.
Now, where's this rock?
Not in here.
Where were you?
Maybe over here.
Oh, we have 13 coins.
Ooh, oh, I really want that one.
But I can't afford it.
Oh, no, that's so sad.
Can we get two coins somehow?
Maybe if we find this rock.
Maybe it'll have coins inside.
Man, where is this rock?
I'm losing my mind.
It's not here.
It's not in there.
It's got to be over here.
There it is.
Oh, man.
Okay, we're going to blow this up.
We're going to get money.
Yeah!
Fuck, yeah, dude.
That's insane.
Back to the shop, baby.
Here.
Give me that damage.
I do like the champion monsters.
Higher chance of getting rewards, right?
Dude, my frickin' desk is shaking.
Even though my washing machine is in the other room.
That's insane.
Okay, let's go.
Sounds like there's someone with a drill bit right next to my ear.
Okay, here we go.
I'm going to play so fucking well today, guys.
Like, I am in the zone.
Oh!
You can't reach me in here, though.
Nerd.
Boink.
No tinted rocks, and we have a map now that's fantastic.
More bombs.
That's the boss.
Just like that, huh?
I'll show you something cool in a second here.
Oh, god.
Okay, we're fine.
Oh, we got Stephanie Step!
Ah, but I can't do that, not with this character.
We need more HP for that.
Unfortunately.
Ah, you bastard!
Nice.
It's not too bad.
Oh, that's close.
That's not good.
I'm going to have to try and get in via the secret way.
I think there's a secret right here.
Watch.
Oh, no, I was wrong.
I'm almost never wrong.
That's a surprise to me.
No tinted rocks.
No key!
Ooh.
Wait, that's it?
That's this floor?
That can't be right.
I guess we got to go... Step?
Actually, no, no, let's look for a secret.
Oh, you know what?
It's probably right here.
Nestled in between.
Yeah!
Fuck yeah, dude, and we can even... we can go in here now.
Oh, who's the man?
What is that?
Shard of glass?
Blood and guts.
Chance to spawn a red heart when damaged?
Okay.
Taking damage will make Isaac gush blood tears.
Every 20 seconds while bleeding, lose half a red heart.
Oh, that's not good.
Wait a minute, huh?
Hold on.
Taking damage will make Isaac gush blood tears.
While bleeding?
Running out of red hearts or healing red hearts will stop the bleeding.
That sounds not good.
But I don't have any red hearts, so how's that gonna work?
Oh, that's... weird.
Let's gamble a little bit.
Alright.
That's pretty good, I guess.
Okay.
Time for the boss.
You know what?
Let's do the bombs.
Enjoy.
Oh, it was very effective.
Nice.
I'm gonna play it safe.
Yeah, there we go.
Not bad.
Toothpicks, more tears, and shot speed.
That's perfect for me.
We're also gonna go in here, but the problem is...
Oh, mom.
Mom is here.
Okay.
This is the PhD, converged most good pill effects into bad pills, but it gives me damage, right?
Some of them.
But that's three blue hearts.
I think I'm gonna die if I take that, so I'm not gonna take it.
I have good range already.
But where's my health upgrades?
Give me health upgrades.
Let me go check if this room is actually open now.
I wanna make progress on that theory today, on how to open this room consistently.
So, like, why is... Maybe it's just random.
It could just be completely random, you know?
Like, okay.
Too bad.
You're not gonna get it this time.
I doubt it, though.
Cheers.
Okay.
Get him out of here.
A nice key as well.
That's beautiful.
A golden slug.
That's a rare sight.
So many slugs!
So, this guy's making white creep.
I wonder if that's good for me.
I mean, you never want a white creep behind you, right?
Okay, we can go in here.
Finally got keys.
The wafer!
That's really good, dude!
This is gonna be so good.
Very good start here.
I could go in there, or I can go back.
I'm gonna go back.
I'm going back, baby!
Oh, it feels good going back.
The best feeling there is.
These guys are not too bad.
Uh-oh.
He's camouflaged!
What?
What the hell is up with that?
Not bad.
Oh, that's not...
Oi!
I ran into the fire like an idiot!
Man, that was actually really bad.
Mysterious candy!
Isaac farts or poops every 30... Okay.
I do wonder what's in that candy.
I mean, if I can fly...
Not really a problem, is it?
Disabled!
Thanks.
Let's go for the big room.
No enemies?
That's suspicious.
Oh, we got a worm.
Okay, here's what I'm gonna do.
I'm gonna do this.
No secrets found.
Too bad.
Then I take the battery, and we're back in action.
Look at all those items!
Uh, answers reveals the entire map!
Ooh, uh...
Let me see here.
We haven't found secrets yet, so why not?
And... Oh, answers as in answers!
I see.
Nice wordplay.
There's two secret rooms.
More range, that's fantastic.
Oh, that almost hit me.
Okay, nice bombs.
I'm not that rich.
Uh, you know what?
Let's donate a bit.
Why not?
Let's try and get to 400 today in the donation machine.
Let's put it all inside of there.
Oh, we got something over here, but it's probably closed.
No, it's not!
Okay, why is it not closed?
There's also a difference between this room and the room with the...
with the boss symbol on it, right?
Or the big skull or whatever.
So I don't think they follow the exact same logic here.
There's a bit of a difference.
Wait, I took damage from something.
Oh, it was the creep, I think?
No, I fly, so I'm not sure.
Dude, I need health here.
Like something other than black hearts.
This is not looking too good right now.
Mmm, what is that?
Tears up, damage down.
I guess that's fine.
Is there more to it?
Damage down multiplier.
What does that mean?
Okay, we also got speed.
Oh, okay, that's nice.
I guess.
Kind of want to blow everything up here.
Is that naughty?
A little bit naughty.
Okay,
let's go to the other secret room.
Got two bombs left.
Actually, I should have used my bomb card instead.
Forgot I had it.
Very fast right now, but...
Ah, man, with one heart?
This may be a short run, actually.
Like, we have a pretty good setup.
We just don't have the HP, you know?
Ooh, okay.
The question is, should I take it now and...
sort of guarantee that...
or make it more safe to do the boss, or should I do the boss, come back, and then potentially get more HP?
I think I'm gonna have to...
play it a little risky and do the boss with one heart.
Gertie?
Oh, I forgot what you do.
Should be okay, right?
Can you do that?
Oh, oh god, oh god!
Oh, please kill him fast!
Kill him fast!
No, man!
Not like this!
Fuck off!
You bitch!
We're going Isaac.
Ah!
Fuck!
That hurt my soul.
It really did, like, all the way in there.
My soul is bruised.
I'm wounded.
God damn.
What a way for everything to end, and it was such a good run as well.
Okay.
It's Isaac time now, though.
Ah-ha!
That is a fantastic start.
Oh, look at that!
Very good.
Okay, okay, this is actually pretty amazing.
Imagine we get a massive laser in here now.
Okay, that's not a massive laser, that's just a bomb.
That's sad.
There's nothing in the poops, either.
Oh, no, not this.
This is gonna be rough!
Wow.
Jesus.
Nice.
That was clean and surgical.
Good job, me.
Oh, my God.
I can't hit them!
Okay.
Uh,
boss time, not yet, man.
We need an item.
Actually, we don't, really.
You know what, maybe you should make it a rule, just always kill the boss fast.
Because the first boss is actually not that bad.
And we do get an item here guaranteed, right?
Which is gonna make the rest of the rooms easier.
This is actually not a bad idea.
Well, that's a big fly.
What the?
I feel like this boss is changing, slightly.
He's more aggressive with his flies than normal.
Yeah, these big flies have never been a thing.
Come here, you.
Oi, oi, oi.
Yeah, has he ever been farting this much?
I don't think so.
Very clean there, though.
A box.
What's in the box?
Money and a... pill.
Okay.
Rainbow worm.
Range tiers and then the various effects.
Justice.
Nice.
Oh, not that kind of bomb.
Man, this is a pretty good start.
I mean, we got three bombs, two keys, four coins.
Can't complain about that.
I never noticed that we're running around in a box.
Something a cat would do.
These guys are going to shoot.
No, yeah.
Bombs when they die.
The rainbow worm there.
I think it's worth it to get in here.
Oh, totally worth it.
My tier is really big.
Oh, it was a random effect.
Wow.
Oh, that's weird.
Oh, please stop.
I feel like this worm is going to sabotage me.
We got a stepity step.
But we don't have enough healing.
Moms pass.
Oh, that inflicts fear.
I could use a bomb or I can walk on that and sacrifice some HP.
That's a question, isn't it?
I think I'm going to...
I think I'm going to come back.
Let me see in here.
Okay.
I'm going to come back in case I find something that allows me to destroy those rocks in different ways.
You never know.
Yeah, this rainbow worm is really weird.
There's enemies!
What?
I'm trying not to hit anything accidentally, so I buy, you know.
Okay.
Very... I've never seen this.
That is so weird.
Bogo bombs.
We got money.
We got pills.
What was this one?
The sharp plug.
Okay, that's not good for me.
Die-sharp re-rolls all items and pickups.
And the...
That could be worth it.
Maybe.
And wait, is this a trinket or a one-use item?
Ah, shit.
Okay, it's a one-use.
I think I'm going to...
I mean, even if...
No, no, no.
We're going to save this, actually.
We're going to save it, because I don't have the money to buy anything good anyway.
Let's say something really good appears.
I'm not going to be able to buy it anyway.
I'm going to save my money as well.
Yeah.
I'm kind of proud of myself for resisting the urge, you know.
Oh my God.
Ow!
Wow!
Let's look for rocks.
No rocks.
Okay, so hold on.
Get that shit out of here.
I hate the worm.
It is actually terrible.
But I will take this.
Let's go... let's go...
Oh, oh yeah.
We got to pick up this item up here.
Yeah, three bombs, it's fine.
Actually, I should have stepped on it, because I have hearts to pick up.
Mistakes were made.
I didn't think.
I forgot that I lost my blue hearts.
Or soul hearts.
It's fine.
It's time to leave.
Decent first floor.
Now I need a lot of money.
Oh, we could play the arcade and potentially get lucky.
Or we wait a bit.
Maybe we get an item that makes us more lucky.
Oi!
This guy blew up.
We have curse of lost.
That is not good for me.
Come to me.
Oh, he's gonna respawn.
No!
Okay.
I just noticed something.
The second time you kill them, the faster they die or turn into the weakened state.
See, I'm not gonna take that blue heart yet, I don't think.
I'm gonna try and be strategic about...
No, no, take it now.
Because I don't have a map.
I'm gonna forget it's here.
One hundred percent.
We got a stepity step if we wanted to, but I don't want to.
We need the right setup for that.
I'm playing this so safe.
Pills!
Yes!
Experimental pill.
We got the lock!
Time to hit the arcade.
Ooh!
No, but I can't see shit because my map is gone!
Oh wait, that does reveal...
I think it reveals it when I go into a room though, right?
Or maybe I'm misremembering.
I'm not sure, we'll see.
Oh yeah, yeah, look, it's revealed!
Yeah, baby!
Nice, nice.
Fantastic.
Come here.
Blade save.
Oh, we got pills.
I really want that pill.
But first we go in here.
Nice.
Oh, wow.
It's going pretty well.
I'm going to get it.
Wait, there's another pill!
I'm getting it too.
Pills!
Fantastic!
This is a great start.
Ah, sir.
Okay, okay.
Oh, you want to die?
I can oblige.
I feel like I'm in ascend mode right now.
Sometimes you enter that state, you know.
Oh, never mind.
I take it back.
Oh wait, okay, come on.
Well, we got healing.
What's this?
It's a new item.
Sticky bombs.
Exact bombs.
I feel like I've had this before though.
Plus five bombs.
Bombs stick to enemies and release slowing white creep puddles on detonation.
No, I don't have, I haven't had this.
Enemies killed by bomb explosion spawn blue spiders.
Um...
I mean, okay, so I spawn a bomb and then I kick it towards an enemy, right?
That's the way you want to do that.
Also, look at this down here.
We're gonna put, oh wait, but there's no secrets here anyway, so fuck it.
If I can see everything.
I gotta blow it up because it feels good inside.
Right, this is where I was.
It's gonna be a pain to navigate here without a map.
Oh, it's discounted.
One plus one equals exclamation mark.
One plus one free forever.
Fifty percent chance for pennies, bombs, keys and red hearts to be doubled.
Wow!
That is a fantastic little passive effect we have there.
That's gonna be nice.
Really like that.
Okay, this is new.
Yeah, I'm stuck, I can't get out, I can't get out.
Somehow I got out.
It's too narrow!
Wow.
I'm kinda glad I don't have soul hearts anymore.
Now I don't have to worry about that.
Red hearts forever.
Soul hearts, boo.
Black hearts, meh.
Hey, did you hear that?
That means secrets.
Oh, how did I miss that?
That was bad.
Saving those for later.
Whoa!
Look at this room!
What is this?
I've never seen this!
We got the fool.
Two keys?
On a key ring.
Holy shit.
I was gonna say, let's bomb the walls, but we have the pill that makes us see forever, so it's not gonna be worth it.
Cool?
Oh, uh, right.
Wait, I forgot whether or not we found a treasure room.
We have 13 keys though, and 6 bombs.
We gotta go in here.
Oh yeah, 7 coins?
Damn!
Oh, I see now!
The keys on the key ring is because of my item.
This one.
The humbling bundle.
Nice reference.
I get it.
That's why I haven't seen them before.
It's the effect exclusive to that item.
Okay, well, we have a bit of money now.
And I can also re-roll if I want to, but do I want to?
No.
Here's what I'm gonna do.
I'm gonna save until I have 15 coins, and then I'm gonna go re-roll in one of these shops.
If there's nothing already that I want, you know?
Okay, so this one is clean.
This was the secret.
Always over here.
Oh yeah, we got the step-by-step, but I don't remember how much healing we have.
Oh, arcade!
Actually, let me go in here.
Oh no.
He wants HP.
No.
I say no to that.
We gained demon points for that!
Huh.
That's pretty good.
I like that.
Let me just have a quick look in here.
You know what?
I'm gonna give my money to this guy.
I have decided.
It'll pay off.
Trust.
Okay, this... come on.
It'll pay off.
Alright!
You know what?
Take my...
Oh, it'll pay off!
Totally paid off.
Yes!
And now I take this.
I also have another double heart somewhere.
Money me!
Take me to 15.
Beautiful.
Let's go heal.
Man, I'm such a gamer.
That's actually insane what I just did.
Oh, you want coins as well, but you're not getting it.
Not from me.
I think in here we had some hearts.
No?
Where was it?
I had a double heart somewhere.
There.
Thanks.
And then we had this funky room.
I think I'm good for now.
It's time to face the boss.
Oh, we even have hearts here.
Oh, you know what?
I can go back and do two more donations.
I'm gonna do it.
The fastest route is through here.
So we go down, down, down.
Left.
Left again.
Down.
Oh man, it's so far away.
Here we are.
Beautiful pathfinding there.
That's good enough.
And we grab the heart and we kill the boss.
Boom shaka laka!
Oh, I'm stuck.
Well, we go right now.
Yeah.
This way we go up and then up again and then left.
Who needs a map, not me.
I survive without a map.
Monstro!
That's for you!
Hey guys, you like this?
Did you see that tactical move?
Oh yeah, you're slow now, aren't you?
Look at all that creep on the floor.
Oh, that's too bad.
An eight ball.
Shot speed increases chance of planetariums, okay.
Phones a random card on pickup.
Also, we gotta go in there on the left, for sure.
I'll take it.
Doubles I6 score.
Oh yeah!
Gimme it right now.
Shovel?
Ooh, that's exciting.
Contract from below decreases the likelihood of a room clear room.
No, that's absolutely horrible.
Nobody ever wants that.
Hey!
Oh, I should have used the doubling money now.
But, okay, hindsight 20-20, right?
I'm gonna do this.
Hey!
Ouija board, more tears.
Ooh, that's good.
Okay, that's definitely better.
Thanks.
I'll be taking that.
And I'm on my way.
Hell yeah.
Okay, we're back to three hearts, but it's okay.
It's not a big deal.
Oh no.
Okay, I need more damage, actually.
Oh, this is kind of a problem right now.
That was a bit risky.
Wait, am I...
It feels like my tears are slightly homing.
Are they?
Like, are they not slightly...
Maybe not, actually.
That's just me.
Oh god.
Man, they have a lot of HP.
It's so disgusting the way they open their belly or whatever.
Oh, eternal heart!
We're gonna remember that.
Especially because it's on the map.
I really wish I could get this thing, though.
I'm saving these hearts.
Actually, I could walk in the...
Oh my god, my character looks horrible.
Look at him!
What happened to your face, man?
I look like a demon.
Oh no!
Yes!
Cool.
Nice!
We're gonna get the double hearts.
Yoink!
I have a plan here.
Actually, this guy is not hard.
I'm not gonna use my active here.
I was gonna use my active.
Maybe I will use my active.
Okay, kill the small ones first.
How far is so good?
Very clean, huh?
Look how I'm managing everything.
I've never been this patient.
Oh no!
It was almost flawless.
Why did I have to do it like that?
Do you see how I pushed it up there, in case that was a secret?
Just little gamer things.
I understand.
I'm the best.
Oh no.
Okay, he's down.
Good.
Oh, you're shooting fast!
Holy cannoli!
More pills.
Nice!
We need two more, then we can become a real boy.
I mean, man.
We have a blood donation here.
Oh crap, this thing shoots.
Oh wait, I have spectral tears!
I can shoot through rocks.
Hey!
We gotta utilize that.
Nice!
I shouldn't donate.
Not yet.
Okay, mom's pad is coming into action now.
These guys do not shoot when they're scared.
Or terrified, whatever it is.
Oh god!
Come on!
Okay, man, that's rough.
Oof!
I need healing.
Oh, this room looks crazy.
This is for you guys!
It missed everything!
At least they're slowed.
When they walk on it.
Oh, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
This one is gonna re-roll everything.
Should we do it?
No, I think my setup is pretty good.
I'm not gonna do that.
I'll use one bomb.
Nice healing.
Huge.
Let's keep going.
Hey guys, this is for you!
I got hit!
Unbelievable!
Puberty!
We need one more and then things happen.
We grow hair on our balls or something.
Oh, full healing, that is so big.
Magneto?
Oh, that's good.
Very good.
Thanks.
We are rich!
That's what I get in this shop when I'm rich!
That's horrible!
Doubles... bomb?
Oh, I don't have any.
Bonds two red hearts.
Wait, what is this?
I need to see this.
Doubles Isaac's red hearts.
Okay, okay, so that's useless.
This is the one that spawns two red hearts.
Useless.
This one is.
Doubles the bombs.
I don't have any, so I'm just gonna use it.
Bonds two red hearts and this one is also two red hearts.
Doubles... Jesus.
I'm rich!
I am filthy rich!
Oh, look at this thing!
Hey, hey!
Nice!
We're gonna donate everything.
And we're too lucky now.
That's good.
I could buy this, but yeah, I guess it's worth it.
Which card do I want to keep on me?
Wait, Doubles Isaac's red hearts.
Actually, this one is better.
Yeah.
Oh, fuck me.
How am I gonna... Really?
How am I so bad?
I should really not get hit by these guys.
A broken magnet!
I mean...
The double magnet style.
Look at me with my tears.
Stay mad, son.
Oh, I gotta go here.
Um... Do I wanna... Okay, fine.
Boss time?
Dude, I'm kinda tempted.
Okay, here's what we're gonna do.
We're gonna do the boss.
Maybe we get a crazy item.
If we don't, we're gonna go back and use the six dice.
And then we're gonna grab the eternal heart as well, before we forget, of course.
This is the plan.
Let's see what we get.
Get feared!
Moms pad!
Blood everywhere!
It's disgusting!
Oh, crap.
You're gonna jump a lot now?
You're gonna jump a lot?
Jump a lot!
Fuck, I'm so bad at placing these bombs.
Give me health.
Man, I have no damage.
It's insane.
Oh, my God!
Grab that.
Just keep moving.
How many spiders?
Okay, thank God.
What do we get?
Speedball.
Uh, oh, okay, here's the plan.
Here's the plan.
It's not damage.
I'm gonna go back now.
I'm gonna re-roll everything, because I have no damage, man.
I can't keep going like this.
Then we come back and grab the synth oil, or whatever it was called.
Okay, you ready?
3.5 damage still!
Okay, we got a bar of soap.
The poop.
Okay.
Sci-fly.
Sci-familiar that moves rapidly to block.
That's good.
The compass.
Ooh!
Very nice.
Banky is more tears.
Soulheart.
Size down.
Increases chance of chests as room clear rewards, but also increases chance.
This seems horrible!
Why is that even an item?
Cricket's body.
0.5 tears.
Less range.
Tears split into four half damage tears on hit.
Oh, okay.
And steam sail.
Not that I need that.
I'm shooting fast.
Okay, I definitely have more attack speed.
I don't know if this was worth it.
I spawn poops.
I can actually donate some health.
Why not?
You also got to get this.
No bombs!
We don't have a magnet anymore!
We got to go find a bomb.
There's got to be a bomb somewhere.
There's one here, but...
Um...
We got to find a bomb somewhere.
This can't... Okay, hold on, there's a secret here.
I can't get in, though, because there's no bomb.
Dude, don't do me like this.
Don't do me like this.
Not like this.
What's back here?
Let me check this room again.
Huh?
Oh, yeah, that's broken.
I can't believe it.
Oh!
Wait, this one's also changed!
Oh, what the hell?
Not... I mean, it's fine.
I think it's about the same quality as the last one I had.
Good to know, though, that changes everything.
And absolutely everything.
Hold on, I haven't given up yet.
So, this machine here is only going to give me money if I do that right.
Let's go here.
That room... I don't think that had anything.
Aw, man, I can't believe it!
I am so bad!
I could donate a bit.
No, I'm not gonna.
Fuck it.
We're just gonna have to survive on three hearts, which is still, like, infinitely more than I'm used to.
That was probably fine.
Okay, Coin of the Maze.
This one, I think, changes things around a little bit.
Nice.
False PhD!
More damage!
Blackheart!
Good pill effects become bad.
This is good for me because I get the damage.
Yes.
Yes!
Mine is... Ooh!
I mean...
I'm gonna pick this up later because I'm gonna use my luck in the arcade up there.
I have pretty good luck right now.
You'll see, this is genius what I'm doing here.
This is actually so smart.
I'm assuming my luck has an effect on that.
I don't know if it does.
I'm assuming it does.
Like, what else would it do, right?
Ah, man, it's not gonna come to me.
I'm not gonna pick that up either.
Arcade.
Nice.
Let's gamble all our life savings.
We have massive luck right now.
This should be good.
Very nice.
I need more bombs.
Actually, I may as well go donate a bit of health now.
Huge!
Ah, less... yes!
That's a good exchange.
I had so much speed anyway.
That's... not really that great.
Uh-oh!
Good thing it didn't explode on the machine.
Okay.
Dude, I'm earning more money than I'm using.
Pills?
Less shot speed more... definitely.
Shot speed down.
Damage up.
Yes, give me all the bombs.
Bombs are in such short supply right now.
If this bombs a bomb, I'm gonna be ready to push it away from here.
Okay, I can do that again, I guess.
I'm definitely losing some shots or some tears now, but it's all about having a nice balance.
Come on.
More!
Wow, really unlucky here.
Maybe the machine is broken now.
Oh, okay.
Well, it is broken now.
Ah, right.
We can go heal up a bit.
Would love to get this back, but...
I don't think I can.
Wait, oh!
Oh, my damage is really nice!
I made the right choice!
And re-rolling everything.
What is that?
Three dollar bill.
Grants random tear effects that cycle every six seconds.
I mean, I guess that's fine, right?
That's not a bad thing.
It's a net positive.
Maybe, actually.
Let's go here.
Jesus Christ.
Okay, that's pretty cool!
Look at my fireballs!
Dope!
Yeah, this is definitely good.
This feels really good.
The chariots become invincible.
That's a pretty good one.
Let me actually just confirm here.
For six seconds invincible, speed, contact damage.
Okay, so...
Wait, I can totally abuse that here, right?
Check it out.
Huh?
Double active?
Okay.
Not bad.
Wait, what?
Oh, it's the mace thing that's doing this.
Ooh, spider bot!
Yes, sir!
Healing damage to enemies gradually reached.
That's also good.
Let's take it.
Gives Isaac's curse of the lost, spawns one black heart.
Why not?
But maybe we do it when we're done with the level, huh?
What's this one?
The Hierophant!
That is...
Watch.
Two soul hearts!
That's right.
Thank you.
Can't really donate any more, unfortunately.
I'll be back.
There's also another pill I need to grab.
The one that reduces my luck but increases my damage.
Oh, another curse of the lost thingy.
Dope.
Here, spider bot!
Yeah!
I love this thing.
Yo, I have like science fiction shots.
I'm shooting nails?
That's dope as hell.
Wow.
Boss?
Um, not yet.
Not yet.
Actually, hold on.
I'm trying to think.
Maybe I should not convert my luck into damage.
I feel like my luck has been pretty cool.
Like, having luck is pretty cool.
Gives me a lot of stuff, you know?
And makes me, well, lucky.
And who doesn't want to be lucky?
Covers the effect of...
My active is shit!
It's like the worst active of all time.
What is even the point?
That's pretty good.
Ho, ho, ho, ho, gamer!
That was actually unnecessarily risky.
Spider mod is one of the best items in the game.
Because it declutters the screen.
Even though it adds more elements, it actually declutters it.
Okay, uh, wait, wait, wait.
I can go over here, maybe?
Yeah, let's go in here.
No!
Okay.
Fine.
Should I do it?
Yeah, let's do it.
We still have one block, it's pretty good.
It's pretty good.
Uh, let's go in here and blow some shit up.
Because we have so many bombs now.
I could also donate a bit.
I have two half hearts.
Sick!
Blow it up.
Nice!
Okay, time for the boss.
Wait, we have two pills here?
What are those?
Oh yeah!
That's totally cool.
We want these now.
Yeah!
Huge.
Let me go here.
What's that one?
Why not?
This is like the massive girdie.
This is pretty cool, man!
Oh!
Yes!
Great item.
Unfortunately, no deals for me.
So that's a bummer.
We're done here, right?
Yeah.
Let's go.
Oh man, I feel good.
Spectacular feeling.
That's being had right now.
I bet at some point in the future I'll be able to look at all these different effects my tears have and go, Oh yeah, that's that, and that's that, and that's that.
Lots can be broken open with bombs.
That's...
I don't care about that.
I don't care at all.
Evil!
Gym.
I feel like I've seen a lot of those chests within chests today.
A ring!
Damage up!
Huge!
I think this is the one with the floor decoration thing.
This brain fell out.
Oh, that was bad.
What's up, mom?
You're done.
Uh, Jira, duplicates all chests.
Ooh!
Okay, nevermind.
Uh, this is the question mark cards.
Don't care about that one.
I'm gonna save this.
I think I'm understanding, by the way, this is a rune that I have.
So when it says random rune, it's one of these types of weird...
Well, minerals.
Marie.
Not crystals.
Thingies.
You know what I mean.
I'm doing so much damage, and it feels amazing.
We got a dick spot here!
Not that we can do anything about it.
Alright.
For later.
Nothing else in here.
No tinted rucks.
Let me in.
Oh my god.
Let's see.
Twenty-nine buckaroos.
Mom's box.
More luck.
Sponsored trinket.
Oh, what is this?
A good one.
Very nice.
Sponsored trinket.
So let's see what we get.
Thirty percent chance for the treasure rooms.
Yes!
We like that one.
That's a very good one.
Tarot card.
We don't know what that is.
The hangman!
I'll be back for...
Oh wait, I could have actually used Jarrah in here.
Wait!
I wonder if I can use that in the devil room.
Hmm.
That sounds pretty cool.
I'll be back.
There's a treasure room I haven't gone yet.
Or explored yet.
Definitely gotta do that.
Holy shit.
Oh man, that is so satisfying!
Yes.
Acid baby.
Falling familiar that drops a pill every seven rooms!
We're gonna get acid!
Consuming a pill triggers acid baby to instantly damage all enemies in the current room.
That is pretty damn good.
We're shooting P now.
Richness.
Oh god.
I could go in here.
And I think I will go in there.
But wait, wait, wait, wait.
The hangman.
I'm actually gonna go grab Jarrah.
And the reason is, you'll see, it's actually quite smart.
I'm gonna grab this guy.
We're gonna go to the boss.
We're gonna see if we're gonna get a...
a devil situation going.
And if we do, I'm gonna try and use it.
We actually have a hundred percent devil right now.
I wonder if that simply means that there's a hundred percent chance I'm gonna get a devil deal.
It's against the war.
Okay, he's gonna charge, that's fine.
Charge all you want, sir.
I don't care.
That's cool.
He has a lot of HP.
Kill him.
I mean, yeah, we got the devil thing.
So, you know.
Not bad.
The pact.
Tears, damage to... ooh, that is pretty good.
I mean...
Oh, it is two hearts, though.
I'm gonna try this, I just wanna see if it works.
No!
Wait.
Okay, I guess it doesn't.
That's too bad.
Let's take it.
This may have been a mistake.
Whoa, what is that?
I'm shooting scythes!
What the hell, man?
That is crazy.
I've never seen that.
Looks really good.
Use diaper.
33% chance to gain the scatole effect for the room.
That is the one that makes spiders less dangerous, right?
Spawns two blue flies when entering a new combat room.
I mean, since we already had the treasure room, so I guess we'll do this now.
Maybe I'll come back and grab the other one again later.
Oh, I can't get in there, yes I can, kidding.
Beautiful.
Two red hearts, that's actually not too bad.
We got a couple more rooms to explore.
Yo!
Wow, you're not even gonna...
Huh.
Let's do this.
Watch this, watch this.
This is so smart, what I'm about to do.
Wait, wait, hold on.
Bro.
Yeah!
Oh God!
Oh no, I ended up losing that black heart anyway, I can't believe it.
Ah, not again, it could have gotten worse!
What a fail.
Absolutely horrible.
More tears, yes!
Oh, that's huge.
That is very good, that is very good.
Skadoodle.
Skatole.
Ah, go here.
Ah ha!
Amnesia?
That's good.
Taking three gives the...
I already took two, didn't I?
I'm an adult!
What does it do?
I don't know what it did.
I'm gonna donate.
Okay.
Let's go heal.
Oh shit!
We grab this one instead.
This run is definitely very good so far.
I just need to, you know, really think things through here.
Oh hell no.
Wow!
I gained a luck!
Why is that?
Interesting.
I don't understand why that happened.
But I'll take it, I mean, sure.
Oh wait, no!
I lost the luck again.
Wait, did I?
Okay, hold on.
I don't know what's happening.
I don't know what's going on.
I'm gonna try and grab this pill without getting hit.
The precision input master is at it again.
Did you see that?
That is crazy.
Would I like to go over here?
Wait, we have amnesia.
You know what?
I'm actually gonna note this down.
Curse of the Lost and Black Hearts.
Yeah.
Okay, let's see.
That's a pill.
Amnesia.
Curse of Lost.
Black Hearts.
Nice.
What's this?
Minus one lock?
Oh, actually, yes.
Yes, we'll do it.
I gained a lock just before, so it's totally cool, right?
Right.
Do I go in there?
I'm gonna lose a bit of my Black Heart if I do, but it could be worth it.
Minus tears plus damage.
I actually think tears are more valuable to me now.
I'm getting too much money.
Yeah, that's okay.
I think we're done now.
Time to get out.
That was one thing I wanted to do before I left, but I forgot what it was.
Was it this card in here?
Copy the effect of I6...
Oh, I mean...
Why not?
Flat file.
Causes all spikes on obstacles, doors, and chests to retract.
Bosses, spike attacks, grudge, and a ball, and chains have their spikes retracted?
Wait, causes all spikes on...
Not just for the room, right?
That's permanent.
That sounds really good for me.
I've had many issues with spikes today.
I gained a lock!
Why did I gain a lock?
I lost it.
It's part of the random transformations that's happening with my tears, I think.
Which one is it?
Is it this one?
No, not that one.
Wait, I'm so confused.
This one grants random tear effects that cycle every six seconds.
So I guess some tear effects also affect my luck?
Isn't that weird?
I thought it would only be like, shot speed, or damage, or stuff like that, you know?
But okay.
We're gonna use this, of course.
But only right when we are about to leave.
Oh, this one could also be good.
No, no, no.
We need the spikes.
The spike protection is good.
Umm...
Yes...
Wait a minute, we have a shop up there with a bunch of stuff in it.
I gotta go check it again.
I do not recall what is left there.
It could be huge.
Oh yeah, definitely.
Even take this.
Mom's pearl, 20% increased chance of finding soul hearts, black hearts, and bone hearts.
BONE HEART?!
What the hell is a bone heart?!
Oh man, now I kinda want that.
Ooh, I kinda want that.
I think it's gonna be better for me.
Yeah, this is a good idea.
I'll take that instead.
Oh, I didn't mean to.
Okay.
Alright, time to get out.
We're gonna eat this pill before we do.
There we go.
And let's go.
Now is the mom time!
Curse up the lost.
Oh wait, I...
Maybe this is just a coincidence.
But I thought it only lasted for the floor I was on.
Oh, this room again.
Less tears, more damage.
Less shot speed, more damage.
Shot speed is also pretty good to have.
I'm gonna keep it.
Very good.
Anzus.
Oh yeah, that's good.
Wait, does this work?
When I have Curse of the Lost, is it gonna counteract?
Let's try.
Fuck.
I think I may have wasted it.
Aw, man.
I was hoping.
I really could have used a flat file right now.
Huh?
Cursed skull?
When damaged, so Hothheart remaining, Isaac instantly tell...
No.
No, no, no.
Not on your life.
Uh, I will do this.
We just gotta be quick.
No!
Alright.
Sure, dude.
See you later.
That's just stupid.
Dumb.
Mom?
Come on, then.
I knew you were gonna come in for seconds.
I know your methods.
Lazy worm, more damage, less shot speed.
That's a lot of less shot speed, though.
No thanks.
Not worth.
Wow, this attack is crazy, dude!
Can I please have it forever?
What the hell?
Nice.
Three.
Ringworm.
Spectral tears, tears travel.
Wait a minute.
Ooh!
Hold on, now!
I think I like what I see!
Taurus, less speed.
While in a room with enemies, Isaac gains a stacking speed bonus over time.
Once per room, maximum speed is reached.
He gains an invincibility.
The invincibility is active.
Isaac deals...
Okay.
I guess that's good.
Okay, I'm actually not sure if this is better or not than what I had before.
We're gonna experiment a little bit.
Health down!
Nope.
Well, wait a minute.
It turns into a health uphill if Isaac has one heart a fewer.
That is actually crucial information.
Let's see here.
Health down.
Let me write that.
Uh, good if at one health.
Gives one health.
Yeah.
Okay.
Whoa!
Wow!
Did you see that shit?
That is pretty damn cool, huh?
Safety cap?
At least he ends up finding a pill.
Oh, nice!
Alright, we gotta go full pill.
Fuck the worm.
Belief.
Maybe I'll come back to the worm later.
Dude, what are my shots?
It's insane.
I hate being lost on the map.
It's not good.
Give me all the pills in the world.
Uh, minus... you know what?
Why not?
Fuck it.
We've used all our luck anyway.
We are now unlucky.
I think I'm happy with that.
Okay, I haven't been here.
That's good.
I think I should start experimenting with the finding secrets.
Okay, nothing.
This is so good, though.
Kinda wish I didn't remove my luck now.
But it is what it is.
Spending all of my money.
We could get, like, black hearts, I guess.
Or soul hearts, as well.
I'm definitely feeling the difference when I don't have a lot of luck.
Like, I can tell I'm not getting as much or as good items.
Yeah.
Okay, that was pretty good, I guess.
Okay, let's save some money for this.
What's that?
Magic fingers consumes one coin to damage all enemies in the room.
Whoa!
I feel like we should try that!
At this point, I mean, what is money anyway, right?
Actually, I used this to spawn another trinket.
The jawbreaker.
20% chance to fire a toothshot.
Chancing increases with luck.
I mean, I already shoot random... Oh, I see tooth.
Yeah, I see the teeth.
Is that good, though?
Like, what does that do?
They break into smaller teeth, and then they shoot off in random directions.
That's pretty good, I guess.
But I want pills.
And I want this.
We'll see if... Maybe I come back, I guess.
I gotta find more coins now so I can start shooting.
Oh, man, I don't know if I've been here before.
I haven't.
Dude, I'm being saved by this little spider.
The spider is goaded.
Let me try and destroy this.
Ah!
There we go, baby.
Very nice.
Whoa.
25% chance to gain a random passive mushroom effect.
Man, I have seen so many trinkets in this run.
It's crazy.
I like my pills, though.
I need more pills.
I would like to get a bit more HP as well.
I'm not super happy with my current HP situation.
I got a pill over there.
And a rune that we don't know what is.
But I gotta walk across the freaking thingies.
I really should have kept the flat file.
What is this pill?
Oh, that's good.
I'm already lost.
But it's gonna be...
I mean, I'm not gonna gain anything, actually.
I'm gonna do this.
Huge.
Harkalas destroys all breakable obstacles and tourists.
Wait, there's more?
Kills or removes the armor from many stone enemies?
Okay.
Actually, hold on.
I think this is worth it, because we have a little invincibility after stepping on this.
Are you ready?
You see that?
Okay, now we leave.
I can't wait to try my coin machine.
It's probably gonna be a lot of damage, right?
Oh, notice this!
Moms Pearl is now 10%.
It scales with luck.
It's at 20% before.
Interesting.
Luck apparently changes the items directly.
What the hell, man?
Also, where is the boss?
You up here?
There you are.
It's Mom!
Okay.
We're gonna slot coins.
That's so cool!
Not that we need it.
Retrovision spawns a Blackheart.
Nice.
And then we have the supper.
Yeah, that's huge.
Fantastic.
We don't have any deals, unfortunately.
No deals for me.
That's fine.
Okay.
We're still on track here.
It's looking good.
Curse of the Maze.
Oh, okay.
I actually don't mind that too much.
I'm okay.
Kill all that crap.
Oh, wait.
I think I had spectral tears for a second there.
Random effect.
And now I don't.
Oh, oh, oh, right.
Are we done with the room?
We're not done.
Now we're done.
Aye!
I can't believe you hit me.
I played it so safe.
Less shot speed, more damage.
That is not too...
Let me think.
I think it's worth.
Shot speed down.
It's okay.
Shot speed, I think, is less important for DPS.
Assuming you can actually just hit with your shots.
Wait, I've had this before.
I must have gotten it in challenge because I don't know what it is now.
This was the thing I thought was a dildo, but it wasn't.
It was something else.
What was it?
Some kind of scoop?
I forgot what it was, but I'm just gonna break it open.
Why not?
Flush.
Oh, right.
Haha.
That's true.
Transforms all normal enemies in the room into poop obstacles.
Not affect most bosses or mini-bosses, but instantly kill certain bosses.
That is so intriguing.
I'm gonna keep going with that.
We're gonna instantly kill certain bosses.
I'm looking forward to it.
Or if I'm in a room that is like, oh shit, you know, I'm gonna take damage, now I'm gonna use it.
Like, this room is fine.
We're chilling here, you know?
Oh, did you see that?
We triggered the spikes without... Hold on, can I?
Ah, man.
I wonder if I can actually get in between those spikes.
Lost my black card on it, though.
Okay.
I think if I get one makes you small, then you can get in there.
Wait, why is the boss there?
Oh, because it's Curse of the Maze and it's all weird.
Spawns a puddle of slippery creep.
We'll keep that in mind.
That's X-lax.
Okay, let me write that down.
X-lax.
Spawns a slippery...
...splippery...
creep.
Good.
We got a million enemies, but it's no problem.
It's okay.
Dude, what are those big tears?
Are those mine?
Mom's toenail?
They're in combat.
Dropping the trinket will cause Mom to stomp on its slope.
Wait, I wonder if that's continuous.
Wait a second.
It says during combat.
We're gonna try this.
Wow, that's frickin' useless.
That is so useless.
I thought at least it would be a continuous stomp, you know, at that location.
That I could use to my advantage.
Terrible.
Locked?
Yeah, you know what?
We're so unlucky anyway.
Why not?
Become the unlockiest man in the world.
I dig it.
Get him.
I have a feeling.
Never mind.
I can get across here.
Spend some money.
Oh wait, I'm super unlucky, so this is probably a bad idea.
Then again, I mean, what else am I supposed to spend my money on?
Count of a penny has appeared in the basement.
Unlocking things.
Okay, that's actually huge.
Good healing.
I'm kind of low on HP though.
Four hearts is questionable.
Okay, more money for me.
I need like a black heart or a solo.
Come on.
Man.
So he shows a key now.
He shows different things.
He shows a coin.
So I wonder if this is consistent.
He shows a key.
If I get lucky, do I then only have a chance to get the key?
I forgot what he showed me there.
Damn it.
I think it was a bomb actually.
That was a coin.
Okay, so I got unlucky.
That was a bomb.
Ah!
I think I actually just started understanding this.
Okay, we got some more healing for later.
Let's keep going.
Honestly, we could go step a little bit.
Ah, probably too risky at this point.
I'm going to check for secrets.
Hahaha!
Secret master.
Bombs for you.
Thank you, Shurn.
We can go give this guy more money now.
I had something in here.
Oh, the pill.
It's a pill.
Oh yeah, and that thing too.
We got nails.
I'm not sure what that actually does.
Okay, they bounce off walls.
That's what they do.
Looks really good in a tiny room, I guess.
If you have nails bouncing everywhere.
This is the Taurus effect.
Holy shit!
What happened there?
Laser beams.
Wow, like fish in a barrel, you know?
Incredible.
Honestly, we have a lot of HP scattered around.
We could go do the two-step.
If we really wanted to.
There is a challenge room down there.
I would really like to go there.
Usually rewards are contained within.
Oh my god, what a room, what a room!
Okay, it wasn't that bad.
Definitely looked worse than it was.
Wait, what was that?
Puberty.
Can we become more puberty?
We have four puberty pills in us now.
Oh my god.
It's open!
Yay!
Ansu's vision.
I actually think I'm gonna use it.
Then again, I already did find one secret in this place.
Maybe I shouldn't.
There we go.
Wait, this is not the last one.
The next one is Mom's heart.
Yeah, I'm actually gonna...
I'm gonna use my X-lax against the boss here.
And then I'm gonna come back for the Ansu's for the next floor.
That's the way we do it here.
I could also walk in here.
That black heart, that's huge.
That's not good.
Yeah.
Wait, I took a full heart?
I thought I would take a half a heart.
Maybe it's different on this floor.
Oh well.
Ah man, am I too lazy?
No, no, no, I'm gonna use this.
I'm gonna use this.
I'm not too lazy.
Let's see if this works on the boss here.
I wanna turn the boss into poop.
Or instantly kill him, I guess.
There's a heart back here we can take.
Yeah, we got it.
Uh, go.
The bloat.
Oh, it's gonna be easy.
Oh, wow.
I stood in that a little too long.
Ooh, I lost a lot of HP.
That was actually risky as hell.
Holy.
Uh, experimental treatments.
Woo!
Increases four random stats, decreases two random.
Oh man, that sucks.
That was actually horrible.
That was the worst ever.
No.
I don't like it.
At least we gained a little bit of more luck, so we can do that.
Uh, you know what?
I have an idea.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Let's just move on.
Uh, I forgot to use my ex-lax.
Let's go grab the answers, I guess.
Answers.
I need answers.
And then it's time for mom's heart floor.
I also forgot to use my frickin' poop inspector.
On the boss that I said I would do, and I forgot to do it, so.
It happens.
Maybe I'll try it against the heart.
Turn the heart into poop.
Wait, why is this stone so weird looking?
Okay, no reason.
I am really slow though, like this is kind of a problem.
Ooh, he.
Point five speed.
Yeah.
Good thing I have the sci-fi.
It's gonna help me absorb a bit of damage.
Oh, you know what?
Should I grab the coin thingy?
Also, call me crazy, but I feel like we have a secret right here.
I lied.
It was a bold-faced lie.
Okay.
Jump into the creepy hole.
Here we go, this is it.
Okay, so wait, the boss is up there.
Ooh, I'm tempted to go for the dice.
Ho, ho, ho.
But actually, let's go to the boss area first.
Because I also want to go to the arcade.
I spent my money.
Wait, why are you not dying?
Okay, there you go.
Okay, let's see.
Uhhh...
Which one do I want to give?
Okay, this one.
No, this one.
Maybe both.
I like this one more.
That's all my money.
Wait, that takes a full heart now.
Things are changing.
Good to know.
Blow it all up.
Aha, not that one though.
That's terrible.
Let me actually...
Can we get to the boss from here?
If I blow this up...
What?
Wait, how on earth?
Oh, it's probably going to loop around then.
I see how it is.
I'm going to go this way.
I can get to that, but that would be useless.
Wow.
Another health down.
I guess I do have more chance of getting...
Oh, wait a minute.
Use this?
Fucking hell.
Let me in.
What am I doing?
Oh, that's useless for me though.
No.
Or is it?
It may not be useless actually, if we want to go further.
We got to go to the other secret room, at least.
At least.
See what's going on over there.
Come here, dude.
Good.
Oh man, my attack speed is amazing.
I priest this?
Oh, let's go in here.
Five!
Wait!
Oh, we got to write this shit down!
Hold on, before we do anything.
Let's see here, let's make a new category.
Let's say dice room, right?
Hold on.
Dice room.
And let's underscore that.
We're going to write...
Six is reroll all items.
Now, what does five do?
I'll be ready.
I think I've taken five before and it wasn't catastrophic, so let's see.
Oh.
Fuck!
Wait, what?
Oh, oh wait, wait, wait, okay, okay.
Write it down, write it down.
Five, restart, current floor.
For a second, I thought it brought me to the next level.
I thought I was going to go up against Satan.
And I wasn't ready for that, because I wanted to kill Mom.
Well, rip eternal heart, I guess, but that's okay.
We got a new arcade.
Um...
Okay.
Wait, these two are different.
This guy is dirty and has dirty hair.
This guy has no hair.
Okay, battery.
Come on.
That's all my money, okay.
See ya.
Ohoy!
That was a lot of money.
I'm actually going to donate some health.
That wasn't worth it at all.
Actually, it was.
I think I got five coins.
This one's going to eat all my money.
That's crazy.
Oh!
Huge.
Something opened somewhere!
What opened?
Okay, more healing.
Oh, that was so lucky.
Thanks, fly.
Dude, this fly is crazy good.
Might be one of my favorite items, actually.
Oh, nice.
Health down?
Come on, man.
Like, everything is health down.
Battery.
You know what?
Why not?
Turn him into poop!
That is so funny.
Go...
Wonderful.
Man, I'm getting rich again, somehow.
Minus one luck, and I'm somehow just getting rich as hell.
I should buy a lottery ticket.
What?
I thought they went down permanently!
That's just unacceptable.
Oh, coin.
I feel like I need a bit more speed.
This is not good.
And maybe one more HP would also do the trick.
Let's go here.
Okay, actually...
watch.
Nothing happened.
It's too bad.
Oh, this room.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Damn.
We're going towards boss.
Anymore?
Wow!
Four feet slash hands.
I honestly can't decide what it looks more like.
Okay, is it time?
We're going to try this dildo on mom.
I mean, the flush mechanism.
It didn't do anything.
Good to know, though.
At least we have established that.
Oh, I'm taking a lot of damage.
I can't even see the fucking projectiles.
Yeah, this ain't good, son.
This ain't good.
Yeah, yeah.
Focus, focus.
Shoot her.
Why am I not shooting anything?
Okay, here we go, here we go.
We can't be standing there.
Oh, wow.
That was close, that was close.
Oh, man.
Okay, we can't go further down, unfortunately.
But it's okay.
Give me the reward.
Oh, that was close.
What am I finding?
What a butt.
Oh!
At one leg, it's tiny me.
Indubitably!
All right.
A fetus and a jar.
Demo man, lost baby.
Oh, I unlocked a lot.
Oh, man.
I don't have any more pieces to the puzzle here.
Maybe that is only Satan.
Okay, we got to go again, man.
Let's try...
Let me see, let me see, let me see.
What should I do?
Magdalene, no.
Maybe cane?
We can try cane.
Let's do a cane run.
Two hearts and lock foot, so we have plus one lock.
I guess that's the thing.
We have 4.2 damage.
That's actually respectable.
Yeah, I'd say that's pretty good.
Nice.
Scan the room.
Clear.
These guys are going to drop bombs when they die.
No, they're not.
I lied.
Is that the fetus and a jar?
The one I just unlocked?
Dr. Fetus.
Oh, look, I have the top hat on.
Replaces tears with sliding bobshots?
What?
That's a drastic change.
That's kind of crazy.
I don't know if I like that, honestly.
I mean, I guess it's cool.
Blow it up.
Oh, God.
Oh, this is going to be horrible.
Wow,
this is going to be interesting.
At least I can do all this now.
I mean, that's something.
Yeah, this is what's going to happen half the time.
Brother, will you please just...
Thank you.
I'm going to look for secrets.
I mean, no secrets are going to be hidden from us.
Why this guy is so slow?
Sup dudes?
Sup?
Boink.
It is pretty effective.
It's interesting, that's for sure.
No, no, no.
Good.
Huge.
I don't know if I should be blowing everything up.
I want to do it.
All right, well.
This is so weird.
Oh, steam sail could go hard.
I could also re-roll this if I wanted, but let's wait until we get a bit more money.
Thanks, I really need those bombs.
No secret room yet.
Aha, there we go.
Where art thou?
Beautiful.
Hey, money for the shop.
Huge.
Yes!
That is amazing!
That is unbelievable.
Wait, what's the note over here?
Dude, we gotta be ultra careful now.
Again!
Wait, what?
Oh, petrified poop, what was that?
Chance to destroy poop, yeah, that's good.
Oh my god, please don't.
Die!
Door stop!
Keeps the last door Isaac went through open?
That's actually pretty cool.
I may save that.
But for now I'm gonna get my money.
Dude, I don't need more bombs.
Stop with the bombs.
Actually, I can give it to you.
But that's just gonna make you spawn bombs, right?
Nope, nope.
Okay.
Huh.
Well, there you go.
Now I can use my bombs for something.
Nancy bombs.
Bombs gain one to four random bombs.
Does that work with my tears?
I think it does.
Oh, fuck.
This may be bad.
I don't know what half my bombs are gonna do now.
I'm gonna take more damage than the enemy.
What the frick?
This is...
This is risky, guys.
Like, stuff like that.
Oh, no.
This may be a huge mistake.
I'm gonna keep this.
You know what, actually?
No.
I'll take this because if I can actually just leave, it's gonna be massive.
What am I...
Dude, we found one secret room.
We found both.
I wonder if there's more than two, though, because when I reveal the map, it always shows two, right?
I'm gonna say no.
I think we're done here.
It's Monstro.
Like, look at that.
That's crazy.
I mean, the bombs do a lot of damage.
I'll say that.
Consolation prize?
Uh, that is...
Oh, what does that even do for me?
I wonder if that does anything.
You know what I need?
I need the one that makes me immune to bombs.
Oh, imagine that one.
Imagine that.
Ho, ho, ho.
Then we would be rolling.
Okay, um...
I'm not gonna go in there yet.
Oh, shit.
This is a problem!
Hey, oh, we can go down there.
Oh, shit.
Oh, thank God.
What's that?
Spider baby spawns blue.
I mean, whatever.
That's not fantastic at all.
It's decent.
Can I step in that?
Oh, I fly, I fly.
Okay, so we're good.
Lucky rock.
Um...
Ooh!
That's good for me.
I can blow up all the rocks.
Jesus.
Sure, why not?
Wait, what was that?
Actually, we should wait until we find the shop.
Save the money.
Can that damage me?
Oh, I hope not.
Oh, I'm in so much trouble.
Okay, that's big.
I need hearts.
Leech.
Familiar that chases and damages enemies.
Heals Isaac far.
Half a red heart!
Yes!
That's good.
We also have a tinted rock there, see?
Massive.
Oh, hey.
Dude, cluster bombs.
Stop bouncing off it!
Okay.
Oh, man, that is so scary.
Jesus Christ, these bombs are scaring the crap out of me.
I don't like what I've done.
I regret my decisions.
Ha, I can get in there.
Oh, yeah, I can fly across it anyway.
Boop!
Yeah.
Very good.
Damn.
47 coins.
And here's the shop.
That is massive, baby!
Yeah!
What's that?
Stores energy!
That sounds good.
Allows active items to store up the two charges.
Yes!
Fucking awesome.
Do it again!
Oh, I didn't mean to...
Oh, thank God I didn't destroy the machine.
I'm gonna donate the rest.
There we go, 346.
Not bad at all.
That's for you.
This is such a unique run.
I love it.
I don't even care if I die or win in this.
This is just too much fun.
Like, this is incredible.
Look at that!
Oh, we've been here already.
I guess I'll blow that up.
And that one...
Who are these people that come out?
They're gone.
But we found one secret room.
This should be another one.
Hey!
Okay, it doesn't damage me!
Thank God!
I'm so happy!
That is incredible.
Wait, did I just kill something without realizing?
Whoa!
Guys?
We're doing the two-step.
We gotta find the stepity-step.
This is the place to do it.
Yep, yep, yep, yep, yep, yep.
Up we go.
So that spawned another one.
Die!
Okay, they die after a while.
That's good.
That's the boss.
Oh wait, no, we found...
Yeah, we found both secret rooms now.
Where's the stepity-step, though?
Wait a minute.
I'll buy this.
Actually, we can donate even more.
It broke.
Makes me feel good, though.
Let's try and go into that challenge room, if we can.
We can't.
But I could go in here.
Alright.
This may be a...
Oh!
Hold on.
We got evil fires.
I can't think.
Destroy the evil fires.
The question is, do I do this?
Wait, is this even gonna affect my bombs, though?
No, I don't want any of this.
Sucks ass.
Huh?
No, I said no!
Okay.
Let's go back.
Okay, then we go to boss room.
Actually, it should destroy that.
It's gonna be interesting.
Blighted ovum.
I got bombs.
Okay, that's actually pretty good.
Wow, the bombs!
Dog food, yes!
I will gladly munch on that.
Beautiful.
And that's it here.
We keep going!
We got the converter, baby!
Converter power!
Ah!
This is open.
Show me the good stuff.
I'm just bombing random places.
It pleases me.
Watch this!
Yeah!
Predictive bombing!
Advanced technique.
Secret!
Man, it's kind of annoying to kill these guys when you have bombs.
There you go.
Pill?
Something's wrong.
Death.
That's a good one.
I'm getting better at shooting the bombs and aiming them.
Oh, that's huge!
Speed is good.
Thanks.
Blow open everything in here.
I love that sound effect.
Well, sulfuric acid.
She has to fire acid tears to destroy rocks.
I wonder...
Have this even...
Like, do tears effects even have any effect on my...
I'm not sure.
Yeah!
Not that I need it with all the bombs, but you know.
Wait, this is a weird treasure room.
This was a lie.
Oh, wait, this was the treasure room.
Right.
So, I'm rich now, so...
The jars...
Uh, no.
Unidentified.
Moms...
Wait!
Plus two keys.
Doubles the amount of pickups dropped by most chests.
Yes.
We can even do this one.
Oh, I probably should have done that first.
I was hoping for a soul heart there.
I didn't get it.
That's too bad.
Okay.
Backpack is holding two...
Oh!
Maybe we could save up for that as well.
Wouldn't be the worst idea.
At least I'll blow up the machine.
Okay, good.
A bit risky, but it's okay.
Uh, that's the boss.
Not yet.
Actually destroy these rocks.
Dude, this is so much fun.
I love bombing things.
Fuck!
Don't know how it worked.
Damn.
They got blown up.
Uh, oh!
We can go 70 step perhaps.
Ah, but we don't have the room with all the HP though.
I'm gonna blow this up.
Oh!
Get away from me.
We're gonna explode after a while anyway.
What's that, death?
And the other one?
Wheel of Fortune spawns a slot machine.
Oh!
I like that.
Oh, it's one of those, okay.
Get rid of him.
Let's see.
Mom's Pearl!
Yeah!
Massive for me!
That's so good for the converter.
You are throwing your life away.
And your troubles be met.
Wow.
Do not look so hurt.
Others have problems too!
I know.
Uh-huh.
The High Priestess?
Ah, I don't like that one too much.
Oh, man.
More speed though.
Absolutely.
I'll take the 40 damage.
Hold on, so 10% increase in the findings.
Okay, that's just overall I guess.
We gotta find soul hearts.
Jesus!
I'm not even sure how that just happened.
I can't convert!
I need half a heart more.
That's too bad.
The Bomberman gets bombed.
I am the Bomberman.
Okay.
Oh, man.
Come on.
What?!
All right.
Uh, nothing in here.
That was beautiful.
Secret discovered!
Wait a minute.
Uh, if I take this now, I can't convert that, right?
Consumes one soul heart or black heart.
Okay.
I'm gonna wait with this.
We're coming back for that after dealing with the boss.
Hell yeah.
Hell yeah, dude!
This is so cool!
Let's go to the boss.
I'm gonna slap his ass.
Oh, god.
Dude!
The damage is crazy!
Uh, right rage, speed...
I mean, I'm gonna have so much speed.
Holy sh...
Dude, I'm flying!
I'm flying through this.
Uh, no devils, unfortunately.
That's okay.
I'm gonna go back now and grab that eternal heart.
We can lift eternally.
Forever.
Yikes.
Look at the axe on the floor!
We need a shovel.
Imagine digging in there!
Uh, let's see here.
Go to, uh, angel looking, uh, church area.
And dig on the axe.
That's gonna be interesting.
Probably something really cool is buried there.
Maybe Jesus.
We're gonna unearth Jesus.
It'll be amazing.
Wait, is there anything else I need to do on this floor before I move on?
Um...
Let me see, did we have a shop?
There's a shop, what was in here?
Oh, yeah!
I want this!
Fantastic, and we don't know what that is, but I'm gonna buy it, maybe?
The Empress.
What was that?
I forgot what that was.
Oh!
Okay, I guess, okay, hmm.
Let's write that down.
Empress turns you into demon mode.
Right.
Uh, that's good though.
Let's leave.
I'm happy I checked that again.
There's no other actives we can grab, right?
Actually, there is.
That little, uh, person figure on the map.
I think that's the simple for an active.
Oh no, that's a trinket, okay.
Let's see.
Alright, well...
I'm outta here.
We've spent enough time on this floor.
Leaving!
Nice, an extra heart!
Oh, you love to see it.
Bombs for everyone!
Oh, I keep thinking that's an enemy behind me.
Wait, it is?
Is it?
It's a friendly!
Dude, I thought that was an enemy!
What?
It can't even hurt me.
Oh wait, we got a thing here.
Hey!
Pills!
Okay, that's useless.
Okay, I mean, we are so fast right now.
Sometimes I question, do we even need more speed at this point?
I think not.
Check for secrets.
Wait, does that even reach?
What's up, dudes?
Secret found!
Yeah, go in here.
Oh, what's that?
Minimush!
More range, size down.
Ah!
I got turned into a pirate somehow.
More range, size down.
That's good though, size down is good.
So, wait, more range.
Am I actually shooting these bombs further?
I mean, I guess I am when I run with them.
When I do this, they go further.
Yeah, and if I go backwards...
Actually, there are some advanced bomb techniques you can employ here.
Very fun.
You can block their path with a bomb!
More tears, why not?
Wait, does this mean I can spam bombs?
Oh!
Dude!
Opens all secret room doors on my...
I guess I can do that, why not?
We are rich now.
Ow, ow, ow, ow, ow, ow, that hurt.
Yeah, tiny rooms like this are dangerous with bombs.
Can I blow it?
I don't think so, but I'm tiny now.
I'm tiny, let me see if I can...
No, doesn't look like it.
What is even happening here?
Dude, they appear in the wrong spots all the time.
Okay, finally.
More speed?
Oh, wait, I'm maxed on speed.
Two is max.
This is closed, unfortunately.
Should I donate?
Blood bag has appeared!
I can donate more.
Okay, now we go heal.
Got it.
What's next?
We got a room up here.
Ah, I didn't mean to run into that.
Okay, well.
Which one is this?
Oh, that's already revealed, of course.
Oh, that was so satisfying.
Incredible.
I have so many spiders with me.
Not even sure where they're coming from.
Oh, wait, I do actually know.
Which one was it?
Not that one.
Spider baby.
That one.
Dude,
I love this!
This is probably one of the most fun runs I've had so far.
The devil.
Wait, does this actually work on the bombs?
I wonder.
Wait, what is that one?
Spider bite.
Slow effect.
Chance of fire slowing tears.
Chance increases with luck.
So, slowing bombs, you mean?
Dude, just spamming bombs is gonna be so much DPS.
Holy.
Oh my god.
Convert!
Huge.
Okay, we're rich.
Deck of cards.
Definitely healing up here.
Well, I mean, why not?
Oh yeah, we can have two!
True.
That's a random card.
The devil?
Wait, two of clubs?
That is bombs, right?
I mean, I have 25 bombs.
Sure, why not?
I got 50 bombs now.
And infinite bombs.
So I have infinite plus 50.
That's quite a lot of bombs.
Let's have infinite plus 51.
I like that.
Another key.
Why not?
Blow this up.
Cool.
Aha!
What wisdom...
Convert!
How do I...
Oh, right.
Yeah!
Choose your own path.
Two of diamonds.
Ooh!
The devil.
Get a baby...
I can't read it.
I didn't get to read it.
Fuck off.
Rebirth got cancelled.
The magician plus three range.
Homing shots?
That sounds dangerous, actually, for me.
Aw, man.
Yeah, I don't think I want homing shots.
If that is actually gonna work on my bombs, that could fuck me in the ass.
I'm not interested in that.
Damn, son!
You got destroyed!
I wouldn't spoon with no effects.
Oh, speed up.
Well, that's useless.
Too bad.
Hey, what's with all the speed items I'm getting?
Blow it up.
Oh, I can't convert.
That's so sad.
Ho, ho, ho, ho!
Dang, son!
Packalas!
Destroy all breakable obstacles and turrets, kills, or removes the o- Sure.
I don't know any enemies that are armored, though.
Or have, like, stone armor type deals.
Oh, no, gimme that.
Teleport to the shop!
Fuck yeah!
Mom's bottle of- Ooooooh, I like that a lot.
Question mark.
Pheromones.
Pheromones?
That one turns, uh, charms everyone in the room.
Let me buy this.
I had a multiplier.
Oh, it multiplies my hearts, I guess.
Wait, is it gonna spawn my hearts multiplied?
Because if that's the case, we can go step.
This is gonna be a crazy step.
Damn.
This is great, man.
I think the laser that comes out of the bomb acts as, like, a bomb effect, so it breaks things, you know?
I didn't mean to go in!
Oh, well, here we go.
Holy...
Massive.
That went really well.
Match book- Yeah!
Wait, what?
Oh, we got it, we got it.
Uh, convert!
Match stick, uh, chance of finding bombs?
Yeah, right.
That's horrible.
No, thanks.
I've got too many of those.
Let's do... yeah, go back.
We have things to do here.
Why can't I find a step in the room when I finally need one?
Oh, this is gonna be a banger.
Shit!
Ho-hoi!
The world!
Let's do it!
Wait, what was that down here?
Something appeared.
It was mysterious.
Uh, crack this... I mean, that's pretty good.
Two of hearts.
So, let me check this.
Okay, it doesn't spawn them, unfortunately.
The empress for the current room, more damage and speed- I mean, that's pretty much useless as well.
I think I will rather keep spawning pills.
Yeah, I like that.
Oh, wait, we see the whole world, right?
So...
Wait, do we?
How come the second secret isn't revealed?
You gotta look for it manually.
Dude!
This room is crazy!
Oh, wait, I was here already.
Oh, bro!
What was that?
The devil...
It is so weird not shooting tears, man.
The high priestess...
You gained battery?
Plus two- what- what- uh...
Ah, power pill.
I'm gonna go in here.
What is that?
Sacrificial altar!
He demands a sacrifice?
Yes!
The altar is consumed to sacrifice up to two familiars chosen at random.
For each familiar sacrifice, one random devil room pedestal item is spawned.
Excavating it also sacrifices each blue spider or fly, spawning one coin each.
Uh, I have the leech.
That's pretty much the only one.
Hold on.
Okay.
Let's do it, man.
Let's do it.
Dark matter!
Chance for tears to apply fear effect.
Sure.
Maybe that's good.
Can I keep going pills?
I have no more- okay.
Okay, okay, okay.
I just don't think the damage is affecting me, though, so that's kind of a bummer.
Uh, please.
Books?
Oh, man.
Monster manual?
Uh, oh, actually.
Was that for the floor?
Spawns a random familiar that lasts for the rest of the floor.
Aw, man.
Imagine I went here first.
I went- I got the familiar and I could do the sacrifice thing.
We have this guy.
Uh, we don't need that, actually.
This guy wants keys?
Oh, I got plenty.
Wait, Bob's curse, bomb damage, poison's enemies, and bomb explosion.
Be behind poison, guys.
Isaac is immune.
That's good.
We like it.
We like that a lot.
Now we just need immunity from bomb damage.
Come on.
Make me immune.
What's that?
Tape worm.
More range.
Okay, let me check.
So I stand here.
Goes to there.
Wow!
Yeah, that totally works.
This is probably more dangerous than not, honestly.
This small room, it bounces off the wall, hits me in the face.
No thanks.
That's gonna be my death sentence, I can tell already.
Mr. Me!
Spawns a blue crosshair that's sub- Oh!
That's good!
We like this one.
That's a great one.
The ghost's gonna take enemies, fetch items, press buttons, open most doors, and sometimes steal?
I like it.
That's a good one.
Kinda wish I had more soul hearts, though.
Uh, we're done.
Let's go grab the hearts and get out.
Yeah.
Sounds good to me.
Ah, wait, this song.
Uh...
Let's bring that instead.
That seems more interesting.
And what was in here?
Nothing interesting.
Wait, was this fully charged?
No.
We got the hearts.
And this one was death.
That's not very cool.
Heal up.
Let's go.
Not bad!
Not bad.
I think it's bomb time?
Yep.
Time for mom.
Ah, this one's closed.
But we have plenty keys, so watch.
Well, don't really need that.
Ah, this guy wants bombs!
I love it!
I got plenty for you.
Ooh, yeah!
That's gonna come in handy later.
That's a lot of sustain right there.
Come on.
Keep eating.
Why do I have this memory that when you give these guys bombs, they just spawn a bunch of bombs in the room?
Eat!
Oh, yeah.
Beautiful.
Dude, I'm getting rich, but do I even need this money?
Maybe if I find gambling machines.
Yeah!
Convert!
Huge!
What if I use the Mr. Me on this guy?
Can I take this guy with me?
Dude,
I have so many hearts here, I hope I'm gonna find a step room.
Step room would go hard.
Come
on, keep eating.
More.
Ninety-three coins.
Eat them all!
Take all my bombs!
We're maxed on... that's it, that was the last.
Thanks, dude!
I have a lot of sustain now for the future.
Gain battery there.
Easily going in here now, no problem.
Spiders.
Beautiful.
We got pills.
You can't see item descriptions in combat, it seems.
Arms, all enemies, yeah.
Could be good, I guess.
Joker teleports to the Devil or Angel room!
Yes, sir!
Let's do it!
The Necromonic Con, we can get three out of three on Bookworm.
Yield instant damage to all enemies in the room.
Dude, I can even use my thingy.
This is a new one!
Okay.
We're going to take this.
No!
Okay, we're going to try and take this.
Yeah!
Spirit of the Night!
Oh my god, look at my character!
Grant's flight inspect... oh man!
Oh, that's useless.
I already have flight.
Guess I'll take... oh wait, I can take both.
Chance to fire tears to summon a rift where they land.
Oh, that's the black hole one.
I think that's good, man.
I'm taking both.
Bookworm?
I should have paid attention to my stats, I don't know what changed.
What changed?
Dude, spectral tears on the bombs go kind of hard!
Um, wait, wait.
This one did what exactly?
Feels instant damage...
okay.
I think I want this more than...
We gotta run with this for a bit.
At least, just to charge it up again.
See what else we can do with it.
And this one is charming all enemies.
Holy shit, bro.
Alright, don't pick it up.
We can't have any more.
For secrets.
Dude, this is crazy!
Convert!
Oh my goodness, it's so good!
I never had this much fun.
Hey, you like that?
You like bombs?
Hehehey!
The one bad thing about spectral bombs is that they go through enemies that don't stop the enemies in their tracks like the other one did.
Which was actually kind of useful at times.
Oh, it did there.
Okay.
Moms ring.
That's gonna take us to three out of three!
Uh, wait, what?
Grants a weaker effect of a random rune?
Rune shard.
Rune shard, okay.
I have no idea what's happening, bro.
Oh, oh wait, we're rich!
The eraser!
That's pretty cool too!
You know when we have a pill?
Definitely eating that.
Nice.
Uh, what's this?
The fool?
Okay.
I guess we'll buy that, I guess.
I'll take, uh... Oh, wait, wait, wait.
I should probably do this.
No, we're gonna wait if we get a Devil Room.
We have a hundred percent Devil!
Then we're gonna Mr. Mee it.
Ultimate Meeing.
I didn't mean to destroy that!
Fuck me, I should have donated.
Mistakes were made.
It happens.
Check out this room!
Something opened.
What happened?
Dude, I want to find that door so bad, that's doing that!
Uh, go in here.
Wow, that killed them fast.
Got the little flames.
We hate those.
Come
on, man, wake up!
Dude, what is this?
Why not?
Two of clubs, double the bombs, why not?
Oh, dude!
Again!
You know what?
I think it's time we put down the converter.
The converter has had a good life.
It's time to put it down.
Because we can't gain any more hearts anyway.
Converter, you were a good one.
Oh, seven.
Eraser me now.
Full eraser mode.
I didn't mean to go in here.
I'm gonna erase Mom.
Come on.
Show yourself, Mom.
Show yourself.
Haha, you didn't like that, did you now?
Oh,
God.
Toothpicks, tears and shot speed.
Wait, why didn't we get a devil room?
I thought we had a hundred percent.
Oh, we did.
Nice.
It's free?
Oh, I was here before.
Oh, right.
Maybe that's why it was a hundred percent.
Hmm.
That explains things.
Can I even open...
I can't go back, it seems.
Shit.
Oh, no, I missed the secret.
Okay, whatever.
Moving on.
Moving on!
Okay, I'm gonna erase some things now.
It disappeared?
I mean, sure.
Why not?
I'm gonna destroy all this.
Why?
Oh, man, I could have used one more converter, I guess.
That's okay.
Fishtail.
When blue flies are spawned, double the amount.
Wait, what just happened there?
All right.
Oh.
Teleport to the secret room.
Take me.
Oh.
I thought it would take me to the other secret room, at least.
I have no idea what even happened.
No clue.
Dude, the bombs are incredible.
I wasn't sure at first, like, how good the bombs were gonna be, but, man, they are frickin' fantastic.
There's no denying that.
The poison as well is doing so much work.
I erased them.
Get erased, nerd.
I'm gonna try and erase this guy.
Oh, wait, I don't have enough.
Holy shit, dude.
Oh, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Guppy's Pause is kinda useless to me now, I guess.
But hold on, if I pick it up, and then I take it back, it counts as one out of three, so a lot of the times I really should do this every time.
Okay, I'm not done here.
Oh, my God.
I can't even take them.
I'm too powerful.
This is insanity.
We go back, explore everything.
I can't believe I just did that.
But it doesn't matter.
We have so many hearts lying around, it's actually criminal.
Hahaha!
That was amazing.
Root forcing.
Eternal heart!
The poison is so good!
Oh, they're visible.
Oh no, they're digging.
I probably shouldn't have taken that yet, actually.
Don't get hit now.
Ah, we're okay.
Oh wait, the bombs do get stuck on the enemy still.
It's only transparent to objects, it seems.
Okay.
Now we leave.
I actually don't mind having the Hierophant.
It's a little bit of healing.
Okay.
Let's go.
And there it is.
Full HP, baby.
I don't want to see you again.
Get out of here.
Damn.
That one's closed.
Oh yeah, I can leave!
Wait.
Alright then.
I'm definitely going in here.
With all the money we have.
Oh no!
Total muscle memory, because I was trying to shoot the fly that spawned.
Shit.
Muscle memory.
Spawns a portal of slowing black creep.
Something's wrong?
Slowing black creep.
Good to know.
I want this more though.
Wait, this is useless to me now, right?
Oh yeah, I can't take these anyway.
Fuck.
I need the one that duplicates my hearts, I guess.
That would be a good one to have right now.
Is that a pill?
Oh no!
Oh man.
Okay.
How come my Eraser is not...
Oh, it's once per floor, right?
The Empress.
Just freaking bomb everything.
Don't bomb yourself now.
Man, bombs do a lot of damage.
Yo!
Tell me that isn't incredible.
Alright.
Calus, you feel... your feet feel stronger.
Grants immunity to damage from spi... Yay!
Abba, wait a minute, I fly anyway.
So who cares?
Actually, mom's perils is useless now.
So I really should be looking for a replacement.
Something better.
So, the boss is there.
Thanks.
We should go find some HP now.
Dude, we have a step room!
Ooooh.
I am tempted.
Let's see if we can't find a bunch of hearts.
I think we had some up here.
We need, like, a really good source of healing.
Let's just fill up what we can right now.
Some there, some there, good.
If I can't find more though, I don't think I'm gonna do it.
Doubles the keys, whatever.
I mean, I have so many keys.
The Fool.
Okay.
Could actually be pretty good.
Maybe.
Good.
Healing is huge.
Secret found.
Ooh, wait.
What am I rerolling?
The back?
I don't know what's happening.
I'm so confused.
Why did it just blow up?
Okay, well, that was mega confusing.
Okay, sure.
Okay, we're full on hearts now.
And we have the Fool for this room.
Did we find all the secrets?
Not yet.
Oh, okay.
Nothing that way.
Fuck.
That was not good.
That was beautiful.
Absolutely beautiful.
Okay, we're pretty much done.
I wish I could go step, but I can't.
Oh, you know what we can do though?
We can go murder mom and then come back.
Oh my god, die.
Ha ha.
Optimally though, like in the end game like this, you would like to have some black hearts at the end and not just red hearts.
Because, yeah, I think that's self-explanatory now.
All right, let's do this.
Oh shit, the black hole is actually kind of dangerous there.
Blow them up, blow them up.
Didn't even lose one heart.
That was beautiful.
Okay, so I'm not gonna step on that yet, or open the box, I mean.
We are going to do...
We're gonna step on the stepper.
Actually, we do have some healing scattered all around as well.
Wait, wait, wait, hold on.
First...
Okay, so this is not the same.
That spawns...
So this is random.
I had coin, coin, non, non.
Let's see.
Spiders again!
Oh, I...
Oh, spiders, because I have the thing that gives me spiders when I take damage, of course.
So, non, non, blessed.
Right!
You feel blessed?
Four is chest?
Okay, so these are random.
I can see forever...
Oh, yeah, actually.
We're missing a secret room here, right?
It's somewhere.
The Fool.
I feel blessed...
So, what was that?
That was after...
Let me see here.
Shit, I didn't keep count.
Blessed, non, I think this one.
You feel blessed?
Oh!
What's happening?!
What
the fuck?
The blue womb!
Glass baby!
Cathedral?
What?!
The...
Get the eraser out!
Get ready for this one!
Erase!
Dude, this is so cool!
What is happening?!
Jim!
Oh my god, there's new music!
Dude!
Okay, we cannot die now.
We gotta play this.
So safe.
Who is that?
Oh, what the...
They're throwing pots at me!
Little bastards.
Oh, right, that was my guy.
Gambling?
I like it.
Live to die.
Get a baby pet, it will cheer you up.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, sure.
Oh, right, I can't take that.
Wait, whipworm?
What was that?
Shot speed?
Oh, that's good for me.
Better than this one, I guess.
Sunday's on your little face.
No sun race!
But it is Sunday today.
You are worshipping a sun god?
I am actually.
I love the sun.
The tower.
No, no more bombs.
The hermit.
Teleport to the shot?
That could be good.
If there even is a shot here.
What did I just get?
Was it the pool?
You make mistakes, it's only natural.
I know.
Well, that was worthless.
When life gives you lemons, re-roll.
Lucky numbers.
Whoa!
I feel like I should have written that down.
I'm playing lotto tonight.
Wait.
Is this actually going to work?
No, it's not.
I'll take that again.
Dude, the music is amazing.
Five percent chance when taking damage to destroy the trinket and spawn an item from the current room.
I like that more.
Liberty cap.
Gain a random mushroom effect.
Dude,
this thing gives amazing things.
Pathfind.
Hankman brings you no lock today.
I think it has brought me lock, because I have the Hankman and it's pretty good.
Crystal ball, I see my future.
Reveals the map and drops a card, ruin a soul heart, increases the chance of a planetarium appearing.
Alright.
Let's do this one.
No, not the fool, the other one.
The one that takes me to the shop.
Was that the one I had?
The hermit.
Wait, this is the shop?
What do you mean?
Oh, you know what?
Actually, my shot speed is way too high.
I'm going to revert that.
That's freaking terrible.
Yeah, give me this instead.
Oh, that's much more comfortable.
Yeah, there we go.
Dude, this is so cool!
Hey guys, new enemies!
They have candles on their heads.
Oh, Jesus.
Two of spades, doubles the keys, I mean...
I have 99 keys!
I have 99 keys, dude.
That is nuts.
Oh, give me this.
Battery?
Sure.
Beep, beep.
That is a satisfying beep.
Bro, can you please destroy this?
There we go.
I have too much shot speed.
Ah, bastard.
No, don't pick that up.
There we go.
Should I go for secrets, dude?
Also, how did I just gain a heart?
Oh, crap.
Lust.
What's up, brother?
Tears up, why not?
Thank you.
Sick.
Whoa.
Okay, that's pretty cool, actually.
Oh no!
I gotta destroy them all, you know?
It's gotta be...
The High Priestess.
Very cool.
Love finding.
Dude, I really should not have maxed my hearts, I guess.
But you live, you learn.
I just have so many soul hearts everywhere.
It's crazy.
More tears.
Wait, is it actually...
Yeah, I think it does increase my rate of fire with the bombs.
Is that mobs, pearls?
It is.
Range lock and a soul heart.
Whoa, look at this room!
What the fuck, that's super cool!
Dude, what is it?
This game is amazing.
Yes.
Find secrets.
What is that massive bomb?
Oh wait, secrets are revealed on the map.
I don't need to worry about that.
Got battery?
Jira duplicates...
Oh, nice.
So we find a lot of hearts, we're gonna duplicate them.
Something spawned over there.
I don't know what it is.
There's something here.
Wait, did I die?
Maybe I killed him.
I'm a victim of my own bombs.
It's getting scary.
No, give me hearts, man.
Two of spades, doubles the keys.
Sure, why not?
Two of spades, double those keys.
Let me try and understand what's happening here.
I give this thing money.
It blows up.
Huh?
That makes no sense.
Dude, who's the boss here?
Careful, careful.
What is gonna...
Oh, okay.
Am I ready?
Something's in there.
Oh, they're throwing pots at me.
Naughty, naughty.
I took damage from something.
What is... is someone here?
Okay, we don't have a lot of HP.
Wish me luck.
I'm going in.
Isaac?
Got the shit out of him.
Did he just heal?
Wait, whoa!
I'm fighting myself.
On my own worst enemy.
Or something.
I got hit.
Keep bombing him.
That's for you.
Enjoy those.
Yeah!
Holy shit, dude.
Oh my god.
We're actually black.
That is awesome.
The coin bag has appeared in the basement.
Pay to play?
What?
Oh!
Look!
Hold on a minute!
Not only do we fill this out, we fill it out in stages.
I think I just jumped to the next level here.
Meaning, if I kill Satan, I'm going to fill out the half opacity, whatever this is.
And then when I'm doing this, I fill out, or I make the opacity 100%, you know?
I make it opaque.
Let's do a challenge.
The solar system!
I think it's time.
This time, though, for sure.
This time, we're going to win.
We have had two losses on the solar system.
Not today, though.
Hold on, I need a sip of water here.
Let's do it.
This is going to be so different from what I just did.
Nice.
Oh, the shop already.
For some reason, I thought that was a treasure room.
Mom's pill seems good.
Ooh, that's also good.
Mom's box.
We can start saving for some of that stuff.
Oh, he's a friend now.
Right.
Okay.
I mean, let's just go in.
We have all the flies with us.
It's Dingle.
Okay, he's not going to charge yet.
Okay, there he comes.
All
right, all right, all right.
Come on.
I know you want to charge.
Easy.
Underwear is insane.
Maybe not on this character, though.
All right, we can't destroy poop.
Unless we have bombs.
Let's find the treasure room.
Uh, yeah.
I'm pretty good at managing not getting hit by bombs at this point.
Actually amazing.
Ah, we could do a step-any-step, then.
Okay, never mind.
I'll grab this heart and move on.
I could have done one more step.
I forgot this was two hearts and not one.
That's okay.
Uh, go this way.
Aha!
Well, doesn't matter for me.
Well, matters for me.
What's that?
Ceremonial ropes?
Ooh, that seems really good.
Hell yeah.
Good start, good start.
Actually massive.
I should not run into that fire.
Why did I run into that fire?
Why have I done this?
I'm too eager.
We can go step if we want to, but I don't want to.
We need more hearts for that.
Hey, guys.
Dude, how is this happening?
They have a larger hitbox than you would think.
Okay.
Oh, that was a little bit lucky.
Wow, that jump, man.
He came at Mach 4.
I can re-roll.
I'll be back.
Actually, there was a discounted one.
Yes, keys are huge.
We like the keys.
This is going to be a problem.
Oh, no, I'm in a bad configuration.
I got to wait, I got to wait.
There we go.
Engage.
Engage!
Fuck!
Good?
Oh, man.
I'm actually surprised I didn't take damage from that explosion.
Wow, I've never seen that.
This was unnecessary.
I really shouldn't take damage against this guy.
Just play it safe, man, play it safe.
Okay, what do we got?
We got safety pin.
It's useless for me.
And where's the treasure room?
Hello?
Need the treasure room.
Don't hit the fire.
Evil fire.
Push!
Close one.
Okay, actually...
Maybe there is no treasure room when you're doing this challenge.
Because this is...
Yeah, this is very unusual.
I don't understand this.
Man, that's going to make this even harder.
Oh!
Okay.
That's fine, though.
What do we got?
Oh, no.
Come on, please don't take damage against these fools.
Yo, yo, yo.
Lazy worm.
Yeah!
Wait, does it matter for me?
I wonder if my damage actually affects my flies.
Shot speed probably not.
Or tears even, but maybe damage.
Man, me when I'm stuck with a bad configuration.
Okay, good.
The planets are not aligning.
I look kind of cool, though.
I look like an assassin.
Wait, oh, I got a click.
I don't have enough money.
You guys are stuck, huh?
Step poops.
What's that?
That doesn't matter for me.
This matters for me.
So I'm not going to eat it.
Oh, this is going to be a nightmare.
Wait, are they stuck in one configuration as well?
Man, it looks like they are.
Not yet.
Well, if there's no treasure rooms anyway.
Kill the tomatoes.
Good.
Dude, I'm doing pretty well here.
Okay, what do we got here?
Shot speed down.
One additional item will appear in treasure rooms.
Ah, but there's no treasure rooms!
Rip.
Oh, I really want mom's coin purse.
Let's go save for that.
That should be some coin somewhere, right?
Maybe even find some secret rooms?
We got some bombs.
Probably here.
No?
Okay.
Oh, whoa.
Good.
Let's go down here.
There's got to be more money.
Nice.
Good configuration.
Okay, one more coin there.
You know what?
I have a feeling.
Right here.
Okay, then here.
Man!
Come on.
Galadine!
No problem.
Okay, right here though.
If not, it's here.
Yes!
Okay.
I'm going to bomb you.
Didn't do nothing.
I'm not going to waste my black card on that.
I'm going to move on.
Decent first floor or is it second?
I think maybe second floor.
Can't be mad about that.
Goodie!
Oh, there's a second floor.
Get those tomatoes out of the picture.
Oh wait, he spawned flies but they're my friends.
How grand is that?
In fact, I can orbit him.
That is so good.
Oh, that's amazing.
We love to see that.
We even have this here.
Multidimensional baby.
Oh, this is going to be useless for me, I think.
More damage.
Stop!
Assuming any stat down.
No.
It's bad, it's bad for me.
Go!
Let's go flies.
A mini-duke!
This is...
Wait, what was it?
Did it say speed down?
Wait.
No, that's speed down, okay.
Ah!
Oh!
Oh, well, that's not good either.
Maybe.
Ah, it's okay.
This is my friend now.
I love my little spider familiars.
Okay.
No effect!
I feel like there is an effect, but they're just not telling me.
If I eat enough of those with no effect, something happens.
I promise you.
Wow, what a weird room.
A huge lake.
I want to go for a swim.
Aww, that was bad.
Did I get anything?
Nope.
Hey, friends!
We're not gonna step, not today.
We just don't have the hearts for it.
Get him!
Get him, friends!
Why not?
Actually...
Aw, man, I wish I knew of this.
I think... I don't think it affects my familiars.
Oh, this sound is gonna get old late, or like, fast.
I'm not gonna waste my money.
I wanna find a shop.
Huge.
Isaac gets bigger?
I don't like that.
Okay.
Oh, no, it's not a shop, man!
I wanna buy!
I hate when this happens.
Oh, I got an item.
Steam sale.
I mean, that's... I just gotta find more shops than I guess.
I need some kind of modifier that affects my damage on the flies.
The damage is not satisfactory.
Wow!
Did you see that?
Huge damage.
It's Vistula.
Wow.
I mean...
My familiars did all the work there.
Eight ball...
What is a planetarium, dude?
Mom's foot, okay.
Better than Isaac gets bigger.
Moving on.
Still don't know what the timer means.
Also, wait a minute.
Uh,
wait, when did this happen?
It was somewhere around here.
Wait, yeah, this never happened this time around.
Okay, what we're gonna do now...
Sent to a new area.
I guess.
Oh, I thought you were gonna charge.
Good.
I'm actually not gonna go in there.
Not just yet.
He's my friend now.
Boom, baby!
Get stomped on.
Uh, no suspicious rocks.
I feel like I haven't seen one of those in ages.
Jesus, what just happened?
Everything is discounted.
Because we have Steam Sail.
Spawn's a beggar.
Ventricle Razor creates two link tunnel openings, which allow Isaac to teleport, but I mean, is that even good?
When would I use this?
I'll take that.
Oh, I guess it's good if I enter a room where I...
I'm gonna take damage if I leave again, right?
That's the... yeah, actually.
That's when you would use that.
Uh, give me that.
Ah!
Bastard.
I think I'm getting really good at this game, actually.
Copy's Pawn.
Oh!
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh.
Uh...
I mean, maybe that's...
Nah.
Nah, not worth it.
Red hearts, forever, until you get late game.
Bad trip.
Shit.
We could spawn a beggar, I guess.
Judgment.
What am I getting?
Yeah, there we go buddy, high five.
Alright, alright.
I see you.
Oh my goodness!
That's amazing.
Thank you, little buddy.
I'm gonna orbit this guy.
Oh, alright.
Uh...
Ow!
Man, he's disgusting looking.
My damage is kind of bad.
My configuration is bad.
Oh, man.
Fuck you, dude!
My configuration!
Dude!
How are you doing this?
Oh, this is a crazy boss!
I can't not get hit by that.
It's insane.
Kill him.
Kill him!
Get him out of here.
Hoi!
Oh, man!
That was rough.
Holy shit, that's actually huge that I got this just now.
We gotta go heal up.
That was a disaster.
Absolute disaster.
We're gonna explore.
Okay, that's useless.
There's gotta be more.
Oh, man, so many hearts.
Maybe we go step?
There's no step room.
Oh, dude, that takes a while.
Oh my god!
What?
Four bombs!
Oh, but that was totally worth it.
Wow, that was a lot of coins.
Hey, guys.
What's happening?
What's crack-a-lacking?
It's gotta be a secret at the end of the hallway here, right?
No?
I'm trying to figure out if there's a system to that.
It feels like...
For example, nestled right here, or down here.
It feels to me like there could be one here, you know?
Well, that was dumb.
Hold on, let me do it from the other side.
Here.
No?
Okay, nevermind.
Actually, one more attempt.
Here.
Okay, dude, I don't know then.
No idea.
Moving on.
Wait a second, let me try something.
Wait a minute.
Wait a goddamn minute.
Watch this.
No, I decided I want to go back.
Oh, I can't, okay.
I thought I could go back one floor, maybe.
That'll be a cool secret.
Some beautiful damage.
We're chilling.
Ew.
For sure, for sure.
No?
Okay.
I got one bomb left.
I can't be spending these so willy-nilly as I'm doing now.
Oh yeah, they're all my friends now.
I should have... Oh, I can still do it.
Yeah.
Look at this.
That's beautiful.
What's that?
A missing page.
Five percent chance to deal 80 damage to the room when taking damage.
Necromonicon, Black Hearts, and Dry Baby also do this increased damage.
Cool?
Let's do it.
I want to find Necromonicon now, or the baby.
Uh-oh.
Well, okay.
There we see how it works.
Blowing Hourglass reminds time and places Isaac in the previous room.
I mean, that is pretty good, I guess.
Minus one range.
Yeah, right.
Uh, give me that one.
I think I'll take it.
I do like the portal though, but...
Why did I take that?
That was a mistake.
An absolute mistake.
You know what?
I'm gonna eat it.
That's right.
I pick it up, I eat it like a man.
I take the debuff, I don't care.
I'm gonna be a brave man and keep going with the debuff.
I'm excited.
I know.
So am I.
Uh, here for sure.
Finally!
Oi!
I'll be back.
I'll be back for you.
Let's go down here.
Oh my goodness.
Whoa!
Actually got gamer.
Uh-oh.
Can you do it again?
No!
Oh-ho-ho!
Yo!
Yes, he can.
I like that the portal stay.
Oi, yo, yo.
Arcade.
I'm rich.
Take all my money.
Wait, what?
Wait, if he spawns flies, they're gonna join me, right?
I'm mega excited.
There's no stepping room, is there?
I got zero luck, though, so maybe...
Yeah, look, I keep gaining flies.
This is totally in my interest to do.
I'm also gonna do, oh, this.
Was that a full heart?
No, a half heart, okay.
Child's heart!
Ooh, that is actually pretty good.
But I'm gonna keep this instead.
That's more exciting.
Dude!
Look at this shit!
Infinite money glitch!
I didn't mean to pick that up, that was a mistake.
No, it broke!
IV bag.
Portable blood bank.
Deals have a heart to self-damage to spawn some coins.
Damage is red hearts, but okay.
That's fine, though.
Dude, infinite money.
The game is mine, I believe...
Oh, my God!
Infinite arcade fun.
That's been achieved, let's not kill ourselves.
Oh, hey!
Okay, maybe that's enough.
Let's calm down a bit.
Thanks.
Once again, I have achieved ultimate richness.
Oh, no.
That's bad.
Wait, what's this?
Oh, the hourglass, right.
Come on, come on, come on, come on, come on, come on.
Nice.
Actually, maybe I should wear this while doing this.
Money me, money me, money me, money me, money me.
Infinite money!
This is so fucking fun.
I love it!
Yes!
A blue one!
Give me black hearts, too!
Let's go!
Pills!
I don't want that.
I don't want to be larger.
I want to be smaller.
More hearts, more hearts.
Heart me.
I'm not going to spend all my money, though, in case we encounter more shops.
I can't stop gambling!
Health down!
Whoa!
Cool!
I'm taking this, and I guess I'm taking that.
See you later!
That was amazing.
What a gambling session!
Love that shit!
Let's go check if this door is open.
It's not ripped.
It's time to move on to the next floor.
Actually, what does this do again?
Right.
If I make a mistake, I go back and I try again.
It's like putting a save point in a weird way.
Like pressing F5 and then F6 or whatever the keybinds are.
Already?
Yes, Mom?
What is it, Mom?
Mom, will you please appear so I can damage you?
Oh, I guess I can hit you down.
Nice!
Not bad.
Oh, again!
Okay, there she comes.
If I'm not in the good configuration when it happens, though, it's kind of ripped, you know?
Oh, I walked into it, I walked into it.
I did, I walked into that.
Gimme that.
Ah, man, what?
Kill this guy.
Oh, man, bad configuration.
Come on, Mom, do your thing.
Yeah!
Okay, no need to redo this room.
I'll take it.
Although, I wonder...
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Let me think.
So, I just got an item, right?
Hold on.
I just got this.
Growth hormones.
Let me go back.
Aha!
Okay, so I don't have it.
But I wonder if I will get a different item now.
Oh, this is actually exciting.
Can I just keep doing this until I get a good item that I want?
That sounds crazy, right?
This is a very exciting experiment.
Of course, we gotta play this well.
Are you gonna jump on me, Mom?
Good amount of damage.
Oh, shit.
Ah, damn.
That was bad, that was bad.
I walked into that.
Not smart.
Got a bit of damage in.
The ice disappears fast.
That was good, good damage.
Stop that.
Oh, man, that was bad, that was bad.
Okay, it's the same item.
Okay, at least we got that confirmed.
Too bad.
Well, I guess I could keep trying this until I get it done perfectly without losing health, but come on.
I don't think I want to do that.
Tomatoes.
Take him out.
Oh, my goodness.
He's confused.
I'm chugging him.
Come on, then.
You know what?
I'm gonna eat this pill.
Stay mad.
Yeah!
Good pill.
Okay.
Wait, I don't think I've ever seen this enemy.
Oh, he's making creep.
He's gonna charge.
Soon.
Come on, damage him.
You know what's funny?
The solo system is even mimicked correctly with the inverse distance from the sun.
I can't speak while I play.
What I'm trying to say is the planet's closer to the sun.
I'm moving faster!
Oh!
I got 30 coins.
I'm gonna save them, actually, for a shot.
You can't reach me now, can you?
Just gonna wait for my configuration.
I'm just gonna chill.
Love that.
Oh.
It spawns you, huh?
He has been released.
Shit!
Yeah, what are you gonna do now?
You ain't gonna do nothing.
Man, these guys are no joke.
Although if I sit here, they're not gonna be able to touch me.
Amazing!
Get owned.
Things are looking pretty good, though.
I hate when he whistles.
Dude, come on.
Are you done?
Not quite.
Ah, you pooped on me!
Yeah, come catch me.
You can't catch me.
Two of clubs, doubles.
Oh, man.
I have so many bombs.
May as well start using them.
I should have taken that hard.
That was a mistake.
Ahoy!
That couldn't have been better placed.
Oh, shit.
Beautiful!
The virus.
More speed.
Poisons, enemies on contact.
I like that.
At least I get something out of touching the enemies.
That isn't me dying.
Wait, what's happening here?
All right.
Okay.
Weird.
That is just odd.
I'm actually kind of dying.
I'm gonna sit in here.
How did you hit me?
I'm immune.
I should be immune.
Let's just chill.
Let's chill.
Now we're gonna go over here.
Then we're gonna go over here.
Yeah, and then here.
This is so dumb.
I have so little damage.
Man.
You're kidding me.
Dude, I'm actually dying.
Oh, man.
Let's look for secrets, huh?
Not there.
Probably up here or something.
Where could it be?
Uh-oh.
This room is gonna be hell.
Let's kill these first.
So I have some real estate.
Good.
Now we kill these.
Oh, this is gonna be absolutely horrible.
Jesus Christ.
Hoi!
Oh!
Wow.
We got some HP out of this.
That's good.
No.
At least they can't reach me.
This is huge.
Oh, wait.
This guy can reach me, though.
I gotta be careful.
It's not looking great.
Kill them all, kill them all.
Yeah, yeah.
Yes!
Oh, my God.
Wait.
Oh, oh, no.
Luckily, we're chilling, I think.
What a crazy room.
They were moving so fast.
There's a pill in here somewhere.
Oh, health down.
As if.
No way, I'm doing that.
Man, where is this secret room?
Losing my mind.
Maybe up here.
No way.
Well, I don't know.
Let's just go for the boss, I guess.
This is gonna be a rough one.
The bloat.
Oh, this guy is also difficult.
Not a good start.
Oh, yes.
Oh, wait.
At least I can't take damage from the creep.
What I could do is play the bomb when he's about to jump.
Yeah, that's the strategy.
Jump.
Come on, jump to me.
No, I got hit.
Okay.
Wow, man.
Wow, that was close.
Dude, what is it with these fucking items I'm getting?
These are all useless for me.
Spun?
What happened?
Oh, B.
No, wait, wait.
What just happened?
Oh, spun.
I guess I have so many drops in my system, something occurred.
Not sure what.
Teleport to a random room.
I think I'm good.
Moving on.
Okay, we gotta look for HP now.
Oh, no.
I'm gonna hide in here.
Good.
Where's the big guy?
There you are.
Oh, you can shoot me over there then.
That makes things a little more difficult.
You have so much HP.
Dude, this is horrible.
That was a really good amount of damage there.
That was nice.
Good.
Get out of there, get out of there.
I got hit.
Shit, it's fine though.
No effect, I don't believe it.
There is an effect.
There is an effect to that.
I don't know what it is, but it's there.
I'm telling you.
Oh my god, really?
Okay.
Redo!
Try that again.
Dude, he has so much HP.
Ah, no, no way.
We're so dead.
Actually, I'm just gonna stand here.
Yeah, this is great.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Come on.
Ho, ho, ho.
Damn, son.
Sure.
Eat it.
I don't give a shit.
I have to teleport Titus Pills as well.
Oh, no.
Oh, fuck me, dude.
This is the worst type of enemy for me.
Actually, it's going pretty well.
Yeah, it's going fine.
Huge.
I'm proud of myself.
Oh, I used my last bomb.
That was dumb.
Oh my god, yes, please heal me.
Please don't blow up, please don't blow up.
Wait, I have four flies now.
Let's see if it actually is working like that.
Yeah, I'm getting a fly every time.
So even if I lose, I win.
Huge.
I mean, I'm making an army here.
That's going to help me immensely.
In fact, I have an idea.
I'm coming back.
I've got to find out where the boss is first.
Jesus.
I can't waste all these flies on random enemies.
That grants a weaker effect.
I don't know what that means, like what just happened.
Oh, this is my end, isn't it?
It's over.
Oh, shit.
Oh, wait, they died.
Oh, not this!
Oh, it's over.
These enemies, man.
Fuck.
Fuck this!
Oh, this is not better.
This is not any better.
I'm going to hide up here.
Come to me.
Yeah!
I'm scared.
Stupid flies.
I have so little damage.
Wow.
Come on, come to me.
I'm going to wait for the configuration and then kill this guy.
You got to be kidding me.
Okay, one of them is down.
We're going to wait for the configuration.
Good.
Yeah.
Nice.
Oh, my God, you motherfucker.
Okay,
we got to go back and heal.
Oh, my fucking God, dude.
Don't give me keys.
Give me HP.
Thanks, you.
Thanks to you.
More.
And your keys.
I swear to God, I have 27 keys.
How about some bombs at least?
Come on!
There we go.
Flies are fine as well.
We can get full HP here.
The problem is, like, when I meet mom or the heart or whatever, I don't know how I'm going to kill the heart.
I just don't have any DPS.
It is absolutely atrocious.
By the time I kill her, I will have taken damage, like, so many times that I die from it.
Oh, my fucking God.
Jesus fuck!
Yeah!
Huh?
Okay, dude, I lost all my HP.
I am so not making this.
Like, it is over.
Huh?
What happened?
Okay, sure.
That felt kind of cheap, but okay.
That felt kind of dumb.
All right.
I have no idea what just happened.
I guess it was time to die.
I mean, I wouldn't have made that run anyway.
We had no damage.
Well, there it is.
One of the few streams where the challenges don't go my way, but the normal runs go my way big time.
It was kind of the reverse of what normally happens.
Die to fly?
No, I didn't, because flies become my friend.
So I didn't die to fly.
The fly was an enemy for a single frame?
Well, that's great.
Love that, then.
That makes me feel so much better now.
Fantastic way to die, then.
That is just dumb.
Yeah.
Fly assistance.
The flies, who were my friends all along, turned out to be my worst enemy.
Didn't use a rewind.
Yeah, I wanted to use it on the boss, right?
Because that's like the most important thing.
So I was hoping I could at least get enough hearts to get to the mom room or the heart room and then start working on that.
And if things went really bad, rewind, you know?
I didn't expect to die to this fly just now, you know?
That's the thing.
Thoughts on Isaac being a boss?
I mean...
Come on, Isaac was a boss from the start.
The fact that he's still going, even after all that abuse from his mom, that's some boss right there.
But yeah, that was kind of fun.
So many unlocks today as well, and a whole new area found... crazy stuff.
By the way, did you guys like the note system?
It's kind of bare bones, I guess, but it works.
I can even import screenshots if I need to.
So I can take like small screenshots of anything I see, you know, and note it down.
Right?
It's so good.
Especially the pill names and the cards.
Sometimes I forget what they do, right?
But you can see the name of them and then I'll know.
Ah, Jackie!
Ah, fuck!
Man, she just scratched my back.
You're trying to get up on my shoulder.
Not now.
Reminds me of the layered notes you had with Noida.
Yeah, a little bit.
I was using a different program back then, though.
I was using Journal back then.
Now I'm using Pure Ref.
How much do I think I've seen?
Oh!
Sixty-five percent, I think?
Like in terms of raw content, you know?
I'm not talking like, oh, you didn't find this tiny item in that place, you know?
Clueless?
No, I don't even believe you.
I think you're all just trolling me.
Because this is what you guys do as well.
You guys are gaslighting me half the time.
And now you're saying clueless to what I just said, so I don't know what to think anymore.
I think you're double-trolling now.
We're five percent the best.
Ah, right!
I don't believe that for a second.
Stop it.
That's a friggin' lie.
Eye tra- I mean, I haven't ordered an eye tracker.
I just thought about it.
What about a heart rate monitor?
I can do that.
I have a watch that monitors it.
I can probably broadcast that to my computer.
I mean, it's not the same as an eye tracker.
I mean, it's something.
I don't know if I want an eye- I don't want to have a vod where there's fucking bullshit on my screen going up and down, left and right everywhere.
I feel like that would be distracting for people.
Maybe we can- I don't want to buy one just for like ten minutes of fun, you know?
You're not that blind anymore.
There we go, look!
I'm regaining my sight.
And you know why?
It's because I'm eating so many carrots nowadays.
Because I read that they actually improve your sight.
They're good for your eyes.
I'm eating so many carrots.
I'm actually sick of carrots right now.
I'm eating so many.
The clip of you accidentally making a redstone clock went viral on t- I've never made a clock.
I don't know what the hell you're talking about.
Are you sure you're talking about me?
I've never made a clock in Minecraft.
Trading dementia for better eyesight!
Yeah.
Wait, wait, wait, is that a compliment?
Or was that a- hold on a minute, I need to think about that.
Trading dementia?
Yeah!
Because I'm giving up something bad and get something good.
It's a win-win.
Not a clock that tells time.
Different- What?
The clock is blinking device going on and off.
Okay, but that's like- why is that anything cool?
I mean, you put two observers next to each other, boom.
Like, what do you mean?
I think there's a thing on Nvidia to use your cam for eye tracker.
Oh.
I mean, I'm sure you can- there's probably multiple ways of doing that, right?
Most people don't mess with Redstone, even 1%.
Really, though?
I don't know if that's true.
1% is a very low number.
And it's such a big part of the game.
I think it would probably be more than 1%.
You see this intimidating and don't touch?
Yeah, I can see that, I guess.
I think it's also kind of intimidating if people are out there making literal calculators in Minecraft, you know?
And then you go, ah, you know what?
That Redstone stuff?
I'm just gonna go ahead and not get into that.
You know?
You never do anything with Redstone?
Too hard?
Brain too small?
No, come on.
Everyone can learn.
Even I!
You saw me!
Trust me, when I first started, I mean, you can go back and look.
I was- I was not doing great, okay?
Let me just say I was- I was stumbling a bit.
It took me a while.
It didn't come overnight.
That was a lot of hours invested to even get an understanding of what was happening.
Watch ending 10?
Wait, what?
There's a new ending in stats menu?
Hold on, I'm gonna write that down.
We're gonna look at that next time.
It's something I unlocked, I guess.
Random, that's good.
Check out ending 10 in stats menu.
This is like my to-do list, actually, let's call it that.
To-do list.
Yep, sounds good.
Ah, I see, yeah, so when I go to the- because I was thinking about that, right?
So, like, I defeat mom, or the heart, obviously the chest appears.
But then I somehow went on, right?
Or I go to Satan, or there was also that one time when I was digging.
So, like, what happened then, right?
But, okay, so it's just- you still get the reward for that.
That's good to know, because I thought, oh, maybe I- I missed it, you know, because I didn't do that, so yeah.
Makes sense.
I guess that also explains why I got these extra upgrades when I was done with the run, you know?
It popped up and said, oh, you unlocked this, you unlocked that, it's probably from that.
I mean, there's many factors contributing to what you guys call blindness.
One, I do have kind of a big monitor.
I don't know if there's anything to that, but it feels like there could be, you know?
I have to move my head around to actually look at- I've thought of getting a smaller one, actually.
Just for that reason.
But it is very immersive to have a big monitor, right?
The other thing is, I'm talking out loud, so that distracts me automatically.
In a weird way, talking out loud distracts you from the things you're doing with your hands.
Unless you're like, super mega good at multitasking.
And then there's also the aspect of the bias.
You guys think I miss a lot, because there's a lot of people sitting behind my back, so to speak, looking at what I'm doing, but not focusing on what I'm focusing on.
So obviously, you're gonna see things that I don't see, right?
And when you guys play games, this is my theory at least, you miss just as much as I do without realizing.
You just don't know.
So in your head, you have a bias, thinking that you get everything.
Because I think I see everything, which I clearly don't.
This reminds me of the video by Smarter Every Day.
He just released a video about blind spots.
You should watch that one.
Watch that video and you'll know what I mean.
It's like this sort of table of what you know about yourself and what others know about you.
And the things that you don't know about yourself, but others do know about you, is the scary part.
You'll see what I mean if you watch the video.
It's a really good video.
I think there's some truth to what I'm saying here.
I'll enjoy the rage bait instead of getting mad at the streamer.
Okay, that's good.
That's a very healthy way to look at it.
I mean, honestly, if it was me watching, I would probably just sit with some popcorn and laugh at it, you know?
I'd be like, haha, dumbass.
And that's it.
I wouldn't be like, rage bait!
Although next time, next stream, I will actually make it an intentional rage bait stream.
I will do everything in my power to make you mad.
You'll see what I mean.
I have a whole thing prepared.
Oh yeah, I've got flowcharts and, you know, everything is prepared, laid out.
I got pages and pages of ideas.
I'm in the lab cooking, you know?
Perfecting the rage bait.
What's better, card or pills?
Easy, pills!
Dude, what do you mean?
Pills are obviously the best.
You eat a pill, you gain like an extra heart.
That's crazy.
Show me a card that does that.
Pill nation.
Okay, the sun card is good.
I'm with you on that one.
But it's so rare anyway.
Like, I haven't even seen that for so long.
And pills are just more exciting.
I feel like every time I eat a pill, I get so excited, you know?
Like, oh, what's going to happen?
Whereas when I get a card, it's like, all right, I guess I'll see what the card is.
I'm always so excited about the pills.
Gambling addiction.
Yeah, I guess it's fun.
When there's nothing real on the line and just video game stuff, it's fun, I guess.
I mean, I love... I do love consistency.
I love consistent gambling.
You always take the pills, too?
Good.
You know what I mean.
Okay, guys, I'm going to end the stream here.
Thank you for watching.
This was a banger of a stream, man.
We have a win streak of two right now.
Next time, it's going to be five.
At least.
I'll see you.
Bye-bye.
Ice exciting out!